護士應該注意
A nurse should monitor
抗血小板藥物的哪種副作用
for which side effect of antiplatelet medication?
A 血壓下降 B 潮熱
A, drop in blood pressure. B, hot flashes.
C 便血 D 視覺模糊
C, bloody stools. D, blurred vision.
血壓下降
Blood pressure.
C 便血
C, bloody stools.
抗血小板 便血
Antiplatelet, bloody stools.
Antiplatelet, bloody stools
便血 便血
Bloody stools, bloody stools
抗血小板 便血
Antiplatelet, bloody stools Oh, the doo-dah day
哦 今天是個好日子呀  今天是個好日子呀
♪ Oh, the doo-dah day Oh, the doo-dah day
抗血小板 便血
Antiplatelet, bloody stools
看球賽吧 這樣才男人
Watch some sports like real men.
這劇比你的足球男人多了
This has 10 times the emotion of your football.
簡直了
It's ridiculous.
嗨 抱歉 這錢都是濕的 衝浪的人給的
Hey. Sorry, some surfers gave me wet money.
好吧 這是你的快遞單
Well, here are your deliveries.
嗯 我最後能省下650塊
Oh, and I would save 650 Cypress for last.
加拿大培根和菠蘿 不 天哪
Canadian bacon and pineapple? No. Ew.
嘿 他很好人的 你也能享受會兒
Hey, he's cute, and you might have fun.
我哪有時間去享受
I don't have time for fun.
喂 那你才是大錯特錯
Well, then you're doing it wrong.
把它加上吧
Add it to the list.
這個不可笑
It's not ridiculous.
這些情節都是取材於生活
These stories come from real life.
奇奇怪怪的事從來就不會少過
Crazy things happen all the time.
快過來 幫我說說
Come on, back me up on this.
我從不看這種狗血劇
I don't watch this shit.
我聽都沒聽說過 我奶奶那個年代的片吧
I don't even hear it. It's like working at my abuela's.
如果你想在外國佬面前罵我 還是說西班牙語吧
-是啊 他們都不懂西班牙語 -呵呵
再見 女士們
抽取患者肺部的粘液時
When suctioning mucus from a patient's lung,
以下哪個選項為正確的流程
which action completes the procedure...
嗨 孩子們 上車啦
Hey, girls, come on, let's go!
媽媽 媽媽
-Hey, Mom! -Hi, Mom!
快上車 我們得出發了
Move! We gotta go!
不是吧 媽媽 那個標誌
Really, Mom? The sign?
先上車 你再尷尬 好嗎
Be embarrassed in the car, okay?
八分鐘內我橫跨這個鎮拿到這些披薩
I've got eight minutes to get these pizzas across town.
上車
Move!
今天上學怎麼樣
How was school?
還好 哦 別踢到他們
-Fine. -Oh, don't tip 'em.
先生 計劃有變
Change of plans, sir.
機器有些小故障
We're just having some minor mechanical issues.
我們要停靠在附近的碼頭進行維修
We'll dock at the nearest harbor for some repairs
我順便讓專業人員來清理下地毯
and I'll arrange to have the carpets professionally cleaned.
我不在意這些細節 科林
Don't need to know how the sausage is made, Colin!
您說得沒錯 先生
Absolutely right, sir.
他為什麼不接電話
他肯定在漂流狂歡呢
我要他回來
放輕鬆爸爸 你會好起來的
你什麼也不懂!
他也是!
他就是個切了我的膽囊
還讓我莫名奇妙被感染的白癡
我要萊昂納多回到墨西哥
我決定了
我要把黑山的工業都交給他
這太荒謬了!
他沒能力經營跨國公司的
他會振作起來的
就像我當初那樣
1961年的那個夏天
故事發生在維也納
在維也納 我遇到了我的一生所愛
但是媽媽說過 你們是在巴塞羅那初見的
對 我是在哪兒初見她的
但是在維也納 我認識了一個舞者
-爸爸 爸爸 -嗯?
聽我說完
我是有經驗的人
瑪格達 現在不是講故事的時間
我只是說
他應該把公司留給真正幹活的人
那我呢?
什麼?
為什麼你總貶低我們慈善部門的工作
當然
因為你們就是群拉小提琴的窮孩子
世界變得更美好了
你可以嘲笑我 但是古典樂救了我的命
救了你的 是抗抑鬱藥!
-不是小提琴 是大提琴!-你們兩個 閉嘴!
我決定了
是大提琴
找到你弟弟
在這個庸醫治死我之前 把它帶回來
上帝啊…真是難以置信
-爸爸 你該去… -讓我一個人靜靜!
擦拭糞便時
When swabbing fecal matter,
護士應該注意以下哪種行為
a nurse should take which of the following precautions?
拜拜 媽媽 再見 媽媽
-Bye, Mom!-See ya, Mom!
拜拜 要聽外婆的話哈
All right, listen to your grandma, okay?
外婆
Hi, Grandma!
奧利維亞 你去洗個澡先
And, hey, I want you to take a bath, Olivia!
要用香皂洗 好好好
-Use soap. -Okay.
你可能不信
You're not gonna believe this.
還記得我唱的那首《悲慘世界》嗎
Remember how I sang that song from Les Mis
在聖·詹姆斯才藝秀上唱的那首
at the Saint James talent show
所有人都說我唱得如天籟
and everyone said I was amazing?
好了 媽媽 你可以在郵件上跟我說這個嗎
Okay, Mom, can you just type this up in an e-mail,
我上班快要遲到了
because I'm gonna be late for my other job.
碰巧尤金高級劇院巡迴演出公司的製片人也在那兒
Turns out, a producer from the Eugene Senior Theater touring company was there.
他聽得都流淚了
He had tears.
不知怎的 他們一個主演洗澡時滑到了
Anyway, one of their leads fell in the shower,
他們想讓我接替他
and they want me to step in.
什麼 都是什麼時候的事
What? When is this all supposed to be happening?
我今晚就要走了 他們已經準備開機了
I'm leaving tonight. They're already in tech.
別走 媽媽 不到一個月我就要考護士資格證了
No! Mom, my nursing exam is in less than a month
你說好要幫我帶孩子的
and you agreed to help.
我已經72歲了 現在不去實現我的夢想 等到什麼時候才去
I'm 72. If I don't follow my dreams now, when will I?
那就別去 媽媽
Never, Mom!
我們搬到這兒不就是為了我能好好備考嗎
The whole reason we moved here
is so I could study more.
我已經不通過一次了
I already failed the exam once.
別想博取我的同情
No, don't guilt me.
又不是只有你死了丈夫
You're not the only one with a dead husband.
爸爸沒死 你們只是離婚了
Dad's not dead, you're divorced!
哦 對了 你幫我照看下狗狗菲奧娜
Oh, and I'm gonna need you to take care of Fiona.
狗窩留不住她 她有狗窩恐懼癥
The kennel won't take her. She has crate anxiety.
你不能這麼自私
You can't possibly be this selfish.
我也很為難 女兒 但劇院需要我
I'm sorry, honey, but the theater is calling me.
哦 一說就來 他們問我裙子的碼數
Oh! Literally. They need my dress size.
你好 一般是加小碼 但我胖了的話就小碼
Hi, there. Normally a zero, but a two if I'm bloated.
晚安
Good night.
嘿 別熬得太晚
Hey, don't stay up too late.
哦 天吶
Oh, God.
我靠
Holy crap.
到了 我就在附近 隨時找我
Here we are. I'll be around if you need me.
猜猜我在哪兒
Guess where I am?
某個傢伙的遊艇上
Some dude's yacht.
你又到處浪
You little tramp.
我來清理地毯 噢
-I'm cleaning the carpets. -Oh.
哦 天啊 特麗薩 看看浴室
Oh, my God. Theresa, look at this bathroom.
老天 我要是能住這裏多好
God, I could live in here!
啊
Oh.
這裏竟然有糖果 誰放的
And they have candy. Who has candy in the bathroom?
並不是糖果
That's not candy.
對啊 沒人或在浴室裏放糖果
Yeah, because nobody has candy in the bathroom.
哦 天吶 因為這是浴室
-Oh, God. -Because it's a bathroom!
快點 再讓我瞧瞧 慢點慢點慢點
Okay, come on, show me more. Wait, wait, wait.
就是這個男人 結婚了嗎 太帥了
Is that the guy? Is he married? He's cute.
這張照片拍得不好
And that's not even a very good picture.
你好哇 特麗薩
Hello, Theresa!
老天 你好 -Oh, God. -Hi!
順便告訴你 她單身哦 火辣性感哦
By the way, she's single, and horny.
非常抱歉
Yeah, I'm so sorry.
我馬上就出去
I'll get out of here.
不不不 我該起床了 今天有得忙了
No, no, no. I should get up. Busy day.
我要忙.… 唉
I've got a lot of...Whew!
其實沒什麼要忙
Really nothing to do.
科林 送血腥瑪麗過來 對
Colin, I'm ready for my Bloody Mary. Yeah.
調濃一點 嗯
Mostly Mary. Yeah.
好吧 給你看到了
Well, now you know.
一個大男人人屁股上竟有個紋身 說的就是我
I'm a grown man with a tattoo on his butt.
那是斯皮迪·岡薩雷斯嗎
Is that Speedy Gonzales?
你知道還有個帶闊邊帽的卡通老鼠嗎
Do you know another cartoon mouse with a sombrero?
貓實在太討人厭了
I hate the pussycat.
我猜 你紋那個時 是 呃 喝醉了
Let me guess, you were, uh, a little tipsy when you got that?
清醒著呢
Not at all.
我就是喜歡斯皮迪 他跑得快還很可愛
I love Speedy. He's fast, he's charming.
他是只墨西哥老鼠
He's Mexican.
他的智商碾壓那隻貓
He outsmarts the pussycat
還給他的小弟帶美味的奶酪
and brings delicious cheese to his people.
他看著就有趣
And he's just fun to look at.
我叫萊昂納多
My name is Leonardo.
我是凱特·沙利文
Kate. Sullivan.
對於一個地毯清潔工來說 你算非常漂亮了
You're very attractive for a carpet cleaning lady.
嗯
Yeah.
雖然你可能需要去弄弄頭髮
Although you maybe could do something with your hair.
好…
Yeah...
不不不 不是頭髮的問題 是你的臉
No, well, no, that's not it. It's your face.
這個 我是說 臉長得好
Yeah. I mean, it's good.
我很中意 只是
I wanna like it, it's just...
只是有些低於平均值
It's just somehow less than the sum of its parts.
別人說你像什麼動物
What animal do people say you look like?
先生 打擾了 我想你應該起床穿戴好了
Apologies, sir, I thought you were up and about already.
哦 差不多了
Ah, finally. It's about time.
誒 讓傑勒德主廚準備好早餐 然後 炒了他
Um, have Chef Gerard prepare breakfast. Then, fire him.
沒問題 我們能讓他再待上幾周嗎
Of course, but perhaps we could give him a few weeks' notice.
他的妻子很受尊重
His wife's expecting.
但他做的東西太難以下嚥了
But his food is boring.
好的
Absolutely.
你在這呀 貪睡鬼 你好
哎呀 尷尬死人了 我們撞衫了
Well, this is awkward. We're wearing the same thing.
要和我們一起去浴缸按摩麼?
當然啦 我的小天使
嘟 嘟
Boop! Boop!
各位美女 帶路吧
Lead the way, girls!
好勒
Okay.
嘟 嘟
Boop! Boop!
嘟
Boop!
哦 快點掃完哈 很快就要用這個房間了
Oh, try to hurry. I'm pretty sure I'm gonna need the room.
打擾了 船長 怎麼了
-Excuse me, Captain? -Yeah.
檢查過發動機了 很幸運
Checked the engine, you're in luck.
防虹吸閥壞了 沒什麼大問題
It's just the anti-siphon valve. No problem.
修理工跟我的看法一樣 蠢蛋
The mechanic agrees with me, dumbass.
我早跟他說過
I was just telling him
我沒錯 他就是個傻子
that I was right, and that he's a dumbass.
你們說說 這個傢伙怎麼賺到這萬貫家財的
Say, how'd this dude make all his money, anyway?
不是他賺的
He didn't.
他家是世界上最大的建築供應商
His family owns the largest building supply company in the world.
他現在整天幹的就是這個
Now this is what he does all day.
鬥雞
Chicken fight?
我們明晚飛回墨西哥
不要 我們坐船走
爸爸快死了
他撐得住的
他那麼固執的人 不會那麼快死的
聽著
等我掌權了 才不會有那麼多會要開
因為我在考慮
買個足球隊
聽起來還不錯吧
難以置信
什麼
你就是個孩子!
什麼?
公司應該是我的
所有工作都是我做的
你可以接著做呀
很顯然 我來撐門面
你來負責運轉 這是雙贏
爸爸為什麼會有這種封建大男子主義的想法
沒什麼原因
什麼?
我覺得他只是...
愛我多一點
真的 別太難過
聽著 我愛你 我很愛你
但是
你可以不高興
我真想自殺
你自己都忍受不了自己
真希望沒你這個人
你需要放鬆
我叫我的按摩師過來
上帝啊 救救我
深層按摩還是熱巖?
我什麼都不要 閉嘴!
姐弟?
好了 這是我的名片
All right. Here's my info.
以後去了挪威 可以來找我
If you're ever in Norway, look me up.
那兒的夏天可火辣著呢
The summers are insane.
會去的 奧德伐 一定有機會去的
That's happening, Oddvar. That's definitely happening.
你好 打擾了 有人讓我來打掃那兒
Hi. Excuse me, I was told to clean in there.
掃掃禮花筒的彩紙屑之類的
Something about a glitter bomb?
會吵到你嗎
Is that gonna disturb you?
不會 你隨意
No, not at all.
嗯 總想吃些東西 吃什麼呢
Hmm. I'm craving something. What is it?
不好意思 您是在跟我說話嗎
Excuse me, are you talking to me?
甜的 又不是太甜的東西 嗯
Sweet, but not too sweet. Hmm.
芒果嗎 對 就是芒果了
Is it mango? I'm pretty sure it's mango.
不不不 等等 番木瓜
No. No, wait, wait. It's papaya.
是番木瓜嗎
Is it papaya?
我沒法知道那是什麼
I would have no way of knowing that.
當然了
Of course.
你能跑下腿 給我帶點芒果和番木瓜嗎
Could you be a doll and get me a little of both?
什麼
Hmm?
你應該知道我只是來打掃地毯的 對吧
You know I was just hired to do carpets, right?
我就不懂你為什麼不能順便給我帶點零食呢
I don't see why that should prevent you from getting me a little snack.
你難道沒有其他人來服侍 應該有10000個吧
Don't you have, like, 10,000 other people to do that for you?
有呀 但你不就在這兒嗎
Yeah. But you're right here.
好吧 抱歉 我真的要快點掃完
Okay, I'm sorry, but I really have to finish up
然後我要去接我的女兒放學
so I can pick my girls up from school.
嗤
Shh.
可能你還不知道我是誰
Perhaps you don't know who I am.
我當然知道你是誰
I know exactly who you are.
你給我看了你的屁股 還踩了我的自尊
You showed me your ass and did a number on my self-esteem.
所以 我就不能吃水果了
Then why don't I have my fruit?
你贏了 但我不去
Beats me. But I'm not getting it.
好 好極了
Okay. Fair enough.
你被炒了
You're fired.
就因為沒給你拿芒果
For not getting you a mango?
還有番木瓜
Or a papaya.
好 這樣也行
Okay, you know what? That's fine.
給我工資 我就走
Just pay me and I'll be on my way.
我不會付你或者你的公司一分錢的
I'm not paying you or the "We Care Carpet and Fabric Company."
大哥 你那兒的廁所
Dude, you have a toilet in there
抵得上我一年的工資
that costs more than I make in a year.
你雇我來幹活 我干了 你就得付我工資
You hired me to do a job. I did it. You're paying me.
拒絕
Nope.
黑山先生 您說一聲就可以開船了
Mr. Montenegro, ready to ship out when you are.
太好了 開船 大西洋就在前面了
Great! Push off. The Pacific awaits.
再見啦 凱特
Goodbye, Kate.
你就是個混蛋
You are a horrible person.
豪門敗類
A first-class asshole!
"A first-class asshole."
你自己也是毫無魅力可言
You're no charmer yourself.
噢噢 心好痛
Oh, whoa! That stung.
自私鬼 眼睛長在頭頂上了
You selfish, condescending prick!
我敢說你這個寄生蟲就沒自己賺過一分錢
I bet you haven't worked a single day in your entire, self-absorbed life.
我覺得我就差 差 差點
And to think I was this, this close,
請你來我們家的洗浴中心幹活了
to inviting you to join us in the Jacuzzi.
這世上可沒有足夠的盤尼西林呀
There isn't enough penicillin in the world!
不不 停下 停下
No, no, wait. No, no, no.
不 別放船
No. Don't untie the boat.
停下 停下 船長 我還在穿上
Excuse me, wait. Excuse me! Captain! I'm still on board.
還沒走呢
Don't leave yet!
女人都崇拜我 魅力四射又體魄強健
Women adore me. I'm charming, and fit, and disease-free.
哦 別天真了
Oh, grow up.
你不過是個虛榮 生活空虛又膚淺的男人罷了
You are a vain, empty little man,
沒了你爸的錢 你就一文不值
who'd be nothing without his daddy's money.
哦 不
Oh, no!
不是這樣玩我吧 哇 哇 等等
You gotta be kidding me! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait.
跳下去不就好了嗎
Better jump off.
不 我哪兒也不會去 除非你
No. No. I am not going anywhere, until you,
或者你的管家 你的鶯鶯燕燕 給我寫張支票
or one of your butlers or bimbos writes me a check.
行呀 等下一站吧 舊金山
Fine. Next stop, San Francisco.
好呀 接下來12個小時 我會讓你如坐針氈的
Fine. I'll be a pain in your ass for the next 12 hours.
我沒想到這一點
I guess I didn't think this through.
是的 你確實沒有
No, you didn't.
我沒想到你要讓我這麼做
I can't believe you're making me do this.
你有什麼毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
等等 我的工具
Wait! My equipment.
哦 當然
Oh, of course.
給你
Here you are.
不 不 不 它們很貴 不
No! No, no, no! It's very expensive! No!
哦
Oh!
等等 我忘了什麼 你的籃子
Wait. I forgot something. Your bucket.
-接著  -不
-Fetch. -No!
而且讓你知道
And just so you know,
我的生活並不空虛
my life is not empty! Hmm?
每個人都渴望我的生活因為這種生活很有意義
Everyone wants my life because it's meaningful.
我恨你
I hate you!
再見
Goodbye.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
現在 我欠了清潔公司三千美元的設備錢
And now I owe the cleaning company $3,000 for a new machine!
而且公司開除了我 他是一個魔鬼
And they fired me. He is the devil.
誰是魔鬼
Whoa, who's the devil?
-萊昂納多·黑山  -他是誰
-Leonardo Montenegro.  -Who's that?
據說他是世界第三富翁的兒子
Says here he's the son of the third richest man in the world.
一個拉丁人 哦 寶貝 你尷尬了
A Latino? Hell yeah. Mi gente, babe, showin' up.
嗨 這些是為船員準備的 不是給他們的老闆的
Hey! Those are for the crew, right? Not their boss
你說什麼呢 寶貝 我已經瘦了八磅了
What are you talking about, babe? I lost eight pounds.
不久之後 我就會撐破我的迷你襯衫了
Pretty soon I'm gonna be breaking out my skinny shirts.
我喜歡他跳舞的樣子
I love when he dances.
背上我的貝克琴
Bring back the Hasselbeck.
你知道我賬戶裏還剩多少錢嗎
You know what I got in my bank account?
42美元 我今晚就需要找到另一份工作
$42. I need to get another job. Like, tonight.
鮑勃 你需要人嗎
Bobby, are you hiring?
可以 如果你可以每天拖巨大的水泥袋子的話
Yeah, sure, if you can haul giant bags of concrete all day.
我們可能會借你一點錢
We could probably scrape together a few bucks for you.
只是邦尼剛開始上大學而且某人買了一艘船
Just Benny started college and somebody bought a boat!
行了 寶貝 我們需要再討論這個問題嗎
Come on, babe, we're gonna relitigate this?
我付的錢比市場價低很多
I paid significantly below market for that boat.
我不得不買 因為它很便宜
I had to buy it. It was a steal.
為什麼我想要成為一名護士
Why am I even trying to be a nurse?
我這輩子只靠送比薩餅和清潔地毯生活算了
I'm gonna be delivering pizzas and cleaning carpets for the rest of my life.
凱特 別這麼說 嗨 聽著
Kate, don't say that. Hey, look.
來一塊麵包
Have a garlic knot.
這會使一切變好一點的 我保證
It makes everything just a little bit better, I promise.
不 不會的
No, it doesn't.
不會嗎 我來一塊
No? I'll have one.
莫雷蒂 傳球回中場
Moretti plays it back to midfield,
像平時一樣控制節奏
controlling the pace as always.
哦
Oops.
等我一下 別轉身
Give me a second. Don't turn of.
還有其它問題麼?
我裝安全套的抽屜空了
My condom drawer's empty.
我處理一下
I'll fix this.
球門前已經沒人了 可是馬格努森猶豫了
And the door was wide open, but Magnusson hesitates...
我說過這個男人總是這樣
I've told the man repeatedly,
在我吃晚飯的時候每九分鐘就打一次電話
for the nine minutes I am having my supper,
我休息了
I am off the clock.
我為什麼付這些人錢
What am I paying these people for?
-我一會兒回來  -好的
-I'll be back.  -Okay.
別太久哦
請在這裏
Please be here.
見鬼 我太無情了
Damn it, I'm relentless.
嗯
Hmm.
耶
Yes!
五個
Five!
珍珠今晚開飯啦
"Pancho's" having dinner tonight!
哇
Whoa!
救我 來人
Help me, somebody!
請救我
Help me, please!
請來人 救我
Please, anyone, help!
柯林 救命
Colin! Help!
-進了  -耶 耶
-Goal!  -Yeah! Yeah!
救我
Help me!
把他安然無恙地帶回家
救命 船長
Help, Captain!
Please! Help!
救命 救命 來人
Help! Help, somebody!
糟糕的晚上嗎 夥計
Rough night, pal?
嗨
Hey!
我不希望你期望太高 女士
I don't wanna get your hopes up, ma'am,
但是我們也許能找到他
but we might have found him.
像我告訴警官的那樣
Like I told the officer,
我不知道今天是哪一天 我不知道我在哪出生
I don't know what day it is. I don't know where I was born.
我甚至不知道我的名字
I don't even know my own name.
我什麼都不記得除了
I remember nothing except
在沙灘上醒來屁股上沾滿沙子
waking up on a beach with an ass full of sand.
你是個醫生 對嗎
You're a doctor, right?
治好我
Well, fix it.
而且
And also...
能給我換一個漂亮點兒的護士嗎
Can I get a prettier nurse?
她是一個漂亮的護士
She is the pretty one.
可能由嚴重的撞傷損害了記憶儲存區
Probably caused by acute trauma to the medial temporal lobe.
失憶癥 是嗎 是永久性嗎
Amnesia, really? Is it permanent?
嗯 大腦很說不准
Well, the brain is a tricky thing.
也許他會在幾天之內找回記憶
He might get his memory back in a couple of days
也許他會永遠失憶
or maybe never at all.
但說實話 我們只有過
But to be honest, we've only had
一次關於失憶的病例在麋鹿灣
one case of amnesia here in Elk Cove
那是一個年輕女人 八十年代的事情了
and that was a pretty young woman back in the '80s.
但願 這是你的弟弟
Fingers crossed, this is your brother,
但是這是一個海濱小鎮 我們這裏已經收留了足夠的無家可歸的人了
but this is a beach town, we do get our share of homeless here.
那麼如果他只是一個住在街頭的窮人會怎麼樣
So what happens if he's just some poor guy living on the street?
那麼他會被送到一家在塞勒姆的精神病醫院
Then he'll be shipped off to a psychiatric facility up in Salem.
哦 天啊  -那的人常常失蹤
-Oh, my God.  -People get lost up there.
我們到了
Here we are.
他真的什麼也不記得了
And he really remembers nothing?
一點都想不起來了
Not a thing.
一百次了 我不要雞肉和牛肉
For the hundredth time, I don't want chicken or beef.
我要魚
I want fish.
一條烤的黑鱸魚加一杯奶油霞多麗
A simple, grilled piece of sea bass. With a buttery Chardonnay.
他不是我弟弟
That's not my brother.
馬上就去做!
Do it! Today!
你還在等什麼
What are you waiting for?
哦 見鬼
Oh, shit.
見鬼
Shit! Ow.
Shit!
見鬼
Shit.
我只有兩個星期的時間 我充滿了憂鬱
I got two weeks. I am having a total anxiety attack.
我不能讓這些女孩在搬家了
I can't make those girls move again.
好的 親愛的 等等 我有半盒鎮靜劑在我的錢包裏
Okay, honey, hang on. I got a half a Xanax in my purse.
我們會想出辦法的
We're gonna figure this out.
凱特 看這個
Kate. Look at this.
我在海灘拾荒者上找一個二手的割草機 看我找到了什麼
I was searching for a used lawnmower in the Beachcomber, and look what I found.
失憶癥患者 就在我們這個小鎮
Amnesia. Right here in our little town.
我告訴你這種事總是發生
I told you this stuff happens all the time.
他不知道自己是誰
Dude has no idea who he is.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊 是他
Oh, my God. That's him.
是那個混蛋
That's the asshole!
一個沒被認出的無家可歸者
"An unidentified homeless man.
普通的惡化的失憶者
"General retrograde amnesia.
曾把希望放在一個墨西哥女士身上
"There was hope a Mexico City woman
附近的快艇上的 也許會是他的姐姐 但是
"yachting nearby might be his sister, but..."
那是他的姐姐
That was his sister.
不可思議
Unbelievable.
我猜她假裝不認識他
I bet she's pretending not to know him,
因此她可以接管公司
so she can take over the company.
他們在某個電視節目這樣做過
They did that on Amor sin Maquillaje.
好的
Okay.
我們現在就去醫院
We are going down to the hospital right now
把他欠我們的錢拿回來
and getting the money he owes me.
為我們的痛苦和遭遇再多要點兒
And add a little for pain and suffering, too.
哦 是的 我會多要很多 他把我當作廢物
Oh, yeah. I'm gonna add a lot. He treated me like crap.
是的 我要新的防滑鞋
Yeah, and I need new cleats.
我們都會有新防滑鞋
We're all gonna get new cleats!
好的 等等 凱特
Okay, wait. Hey, Kate?
如果他知道你是誰的時候都不付你錢
If he didn't pay you when he knew who you were,
那你怎麼會認為他現在會付你錢
what makes you think he's gonna pay you now?
真令人沮喪
This is so frustrating!
我恨富人 他們總能順心如意
I hate rich people. They get away with everything.
但是你知道嗎 這次不行
But you know what? No, not this time.
因為 我不會告訴他們他是誰
Because I am not gonna tell them who he is.
我讓他爛在那裏
I am just gonna let him rot in there.
是的 你可以那麼做
Yeah, you could do that,
或者你可以像他們那樣利用這種情況
or you can be like them and take advantage of the situation.
我應該怎麼做
How? How could I do that?
卡洛斯 你還干辦假證麼?
Carlos, you still making fake documents?
什麼
What?
當然不
Absolutely not.
沒有花天酒地
Out of that racket.
我可是個守法的美國公民
I'm a law-abiding American citizen.
州內的還是聯邦的
State or federal?
好的 嗨 女孩們 我需要你們幫你媽媽
All right, hey, girls. I'm gonna need you to help your mom
找一些老的家庭照片
dig up some old family photos.
我讓鮑勃借我們一箱沒用的瘦衣服
I'm gonna ask Bobby to loan us a box of his useless, skinny clothes,
因為我有一個你不喜歡的主意
because I have an idea that you're gonna hate,
但是你錯了因為這會使你伸張正義的過程很有詩意
but you're wrong because it is poetic in its justice.
-嗨  -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
我來接我的丈夫 那個失憶的男人
I'm here to pick up my husband, the man with amnesia.
你一定是凱特
Oh. You must be Kate?
弗萊徹醫生很高興接到你的電話
Dr. Fletcher was so excited to get your call.
我們也是
We all were.
I'll go get him.
差點忘了 這是他來這裏時身上的全部物品
Almost forgot. Here's everything he had with him.
謝謝
Thank you.
等等 好嗎 你只是緊張
Wait, okay, you're just nervous.
是的 很緊張
Yeah, really nervous.
這很瘋狂而且可能還不合法
This is crazy and probably illegal.
凱特 行了 你去哪
Kate, come on. Where are you going?
聽著 你想被驅逐嗎
Look, do you wanna get evicted?
當然不想
Of course not.
那麼 就照著劇本來 我們有一個計劃
Okay, well, then stick to the script. We have a plan.
直到下個月考試前 鮑勃會僱傭他
One month until the test. Bobby will hire him,
他會是一張額外的支票 而你會有更多的時間學習
and he'll be an extra paycheck, so you have time to study.
我不認識這個傢伙 我不會讓他搬進我家
I barely know the guy. I am not gonna let him move in.
但是你也會在那 學習
But you're gonna be there, studying.
這是為什麼這個計劃很妙
That's why it's genius.
他永遠不會和孩子單獨在一起
He'll never have to be alone with the kids.
來吧
Come on.
你做這些是為了你的孩子
You're doing this for your girls.
我做這些是為了我的孩子
I'm doing this for my girls.
這就對了
There you go.
好的 給你 用這個 鮑勃不會注意到的
Okay, here, use this. Bobby won't even notice.
好消息
Good news.
你的妻子來接你回家了
Your wife has come to take you home.
總算來人了 是時候該出院了
Finally. It's about time.
什麼 等等
What? Wait.
我結婚了
I'm married?
嗨 親愛的
Hi, honey.
我不認識這個女士
I do not recognize this lady.
我恐怕這會發生的
I was afraid this would happen.
我們談過的結婚證明你帶來了嗎
Did you bring the materials we talked about?
我知道這一定讓人困惑
I know this must be very disorienting,
這是我們的結婚證
but here's our marriage license.
我的名字是萊奧·沙利文
My name is Leo Sullivan?
是的 你的曾祖父
Yes. Your great-grandfather...
你的曾曾祖父 芬巴·沙利文
Your great-great-grandfather, Finbar Sullivan,
從愛爾蘭來 在1846年的戰爭為墨西哥而戰
emigrated from Ireland, to fight for Mexico in the war of 1846.
這是官樣文章 不可能是真的
That's gobbledygook! It can't be true.
親愛的 我們已經結婚十五年了
Honey, we have been married for 15 years.
我們有三個女兒
We have three wonderful daughters.
不 我不可能有孩子
No, there's no way I have children.
如果我有 只能是兒子
And if I did, they'd be sons.
我只是說說
I'm just saying.
我有你的護照 出生證明
I have your passport, your birth certificate...
哦
Oh...
這是我們蜜月的照片
Here's a photo from our honeymoon.
我們去了雷諾
We went to Reno?
現在我知道你在撒謊了
Now I know you're lying.
萊奧 親愛的 不要在困惑了
Leo! Sweetie, stop puzzling.
我很困惑
I'm puzzling.
我們是萊奧·沙利文夫婦
You and I are Mr. and Mrs. Leo Sullivan.
我們在坎昆相遇
We met in Cancun.
你是一個導遊
You were a tour guide.
我在一艘游輪上工作
I was working on a cruise ship.
你想起一些什麼了嗎
Is any of this ringing a bell?
沒有 什麼也沒有
Nope. Nothing.
我們在我每次靠岸時約會
We dated every time I docked.
我們會去吃一些冰凍的酸奶
We would get frozen yogurt
在海龜海灘看落日
and watch the sunset over the Playa Tortugas.
那是我們墜入愛河的地方
That's where we fell in love.
聽起來你很浪漫 萊奧
Sounds like you're a romantic, Leo.
聽著 聽著 聽著
Look, look, look.
我承認我忘記了很多事情
I admit there are many things I've forgotten,
但是在我的靈魂深處
but from the depths of my soul,
我知道我沒和這個女人結婚
I know I'm not married to this woman.
所以 除非我看到一些實質的證據
So, unless I see some real proof,
我要去餐廳吃一片比薩餅了 好嗎
I'm getting a slice of pie at the cafeteria, hmm?
祝你好運 瘋狂的女人
Good luck, crazy lady.
等等 等等 等一下 親愛的?
Wait, wait. Wait. Honey?
我並不想這麼說
I didn't wanna say this,
我知道這會讓你覺得尷尬
because I know it embarrasses you.
但你臀部的右邊有個卡通老鼠的紋身
But you have a tattoo of a cartoon mouse on your right butt cheek.
沒有
No, I don't.
你真的是我老婆嗎?
You're really my wife?
不管怎樣都是 親愛的
For better or worse, baby.
行了 我們走吧
All right, 我們到家了.
這房子看起來不咋樣 但是個充滿了愛的地方
I know it doesn't look like much, but it's full of love.
我很窮嗎?
I'm poor?
是啊
Yup.
進來吧
Come on in.
噢 爸爸!
Oh, Dad!
-爸爸! -我們好想念你啊
-Daddy! -We missed you so much.
很高興你沒事
I'm so glad you're okay.
艾米莉?
Emily?
嗨
Hey.
在接受這件事上她表現得過於冷靜了
She's too cool to admit it,
但她是所有人裏面最擔心你的
but she was the most worried of all.
對不起 你們我一個都不認識了
I'm sorry, I don't recognize any of you.
哦 拜託
Oh, come on.
茉莉 奧利維亞 艾米莉
Molly, Olivia, Emily,
你的三個火槍手?
your three musketeers?
不記得了
No.
呃...我得去寫作業了
Uh... I've got homework.
為什麼她們長得不像我?
How come they don't look like me?
噢 親愛的...
Oh, sweetie...
我們一直無法懷孕
We had trouble getting pregnant,
所以我們使用了精子捐助者的精子
so we had to use a sperm donor.
我有不孕不育癥?
I'm sterile?
但這並不能改變一個事實
That doesn't change a thing.
你還是她們的父親
You are still their father.
你為這個家庭付出了一切
You've done everything for this family.
干了兩份 甚至三份工作
Taken two, even three jobs.
我在工作?
I work?
不然你覺得我們的經濟來源是什麼?
How do you think we can pay for all of this?
我想問的是 我以什麼謀生?
I'm afraid to ask, but what do I do for a living?
好吧 在你被解雇之前
Well, before you got laid off,
你是家禽加工廠的工頭
you were a foreman at the poultry processing plant.
幸運的是 波比
Luckily, Bobby,
我上司的丈夫 你打保齡球時認識的
my boss's husband, you met bowling,
在他的建築公司給你安排了一份工作
gave you a job at his construction company.
我知道那是份糟糕並且艱苦繁重的工作
It is awful, backbreaking work, I know,
但能得到它就已經很幸運了
but we are lucky to have it.
我需要喝點什麼 多喝點
I need a drink. Lots of them.
什麼?請你別告訴我我被禁酒了?
What? Please don't tell me I'm sober?
你之前約定三年不喝酒
You had your three-year chip,
然後你就發病了
but then you relapsed
最後在那個海灘上記憶斷片了
and you ended up on that beach.
所以要怎麼做?四天?你只需要再忍四天了 親愛的
So what is that? Four days? You got four days, honey.
-我們還是以你為榮 -嗯嗯
-We're still really proud of you. -Mm-hmm.
我明白了
I see.
不管怎樣都不能喝酒
No alcohol. Whatsoever.
沒什麼
Nada.
我需要用一下洗手間
I need to use the restroom.
我覺得那邊的房間是個廁所
I assume it's that room over there with the toilet.
看看你自己 親愛的 都回來了!
Look at you, babe. It's all coming back!
嘟
Boop.
我不喜歡這麼做
I don't like that.
再來一次
One more.
嘟 嘟
Boop, boop!
這個不可能是我老婆
This can't be my life.
親愛的!
Honey!
-嗨! -嗨
-Hey! -Hi.
廁紙快用完了
Running low on toilet paper.
新的在水池底下!
Under the sink!
那當然
Of course.
對
Yes.
在水池底下 那當然
Under the sink, of course.
請你們回墨西哥的時候
Please keep my beloved brother in your prayers
為我親愛的弟弟祈禱
as you head back to Mexico.
我會一直待在這裏直到找到他
I'm going to stay here until I find him.
活著的或者是...
Alive or...
往好的方面想 諸位 只往好的方面想
Good thoughts, people. Only good thoughts.
我以前很胖?
I was fat?
呃 對 你酗酒時沒能作出最好的決定 親愛的
Um, yeah. You didn't make the best decisions when you were drinking, honey.
明天我們得去一趟二手商店
Tomorrow we're going to Goodwill.
波比最小的衣服一點都不小
Bobby's skinny clothes are not skinny.
我覺得我是海鷹隊的狂熱粉絲
I assume these Seahawks are some kind of sports team and I'm a big fan,
因為我大多數的衣服上面
because most of my clothes
都有這個討厭的藍色和綠色的鳥
have this God-awful green and blue bird on it.
足球 爸爸 這是我們喜歡的
Football, Dad. It's our thing.
我們每場比賽都會一起看
We watch every game together.
有些時候我甚至沒有完成作業
Even when I haven't done my homework.
嗨 所有人都得完成作業
Hey. Everyone does their homework.
也包括我 現在我得把這些胸外科條例背下來
Including me. And right now I've gotta memorize protocols for thoracic surgery.
所以 裏奧 你怎麼不去做飯呢
So, Leo, why don't you get dinner started?
什麼?做飯?我?做飯?
What? Cook? Me? Cook?
親愛的 我知道你大腦損傷了
Sweetheart, I know you had a head injury,
但我們以前達成過協議
but we made a deal.
我為考試做準備的時候
While I'm studying for my exam,
你負責做家務
you keep the house running.
但我甚至不知道怎麼開爐子
But I don't even know how to turn on the stove.
噢!親愛的 拜託別這麼說
Oh! Honey, come on.
沙拉 意大利面 冰箱裏有罐調味料
Salad, pasta. There's a jar of sauce in the fridge.
不會吧
Holy cow.
喔 喔 喔 呃 對不起
Ooh, ooh, ooh, uh, pardon me.
沒什麼比在溫暖的天氣裏來瓶冰啤酒更爽的了
Nothing like an icy cold beer on a warm day.
嗯嗯
Mmm, mmm.
很好
Yes.
呃!
Ugh!
這是我們常用的調味料?
Is this the sauce we always use?
嘗起來沒有味道
It tastes like red nothing.
還有 怎麼才能知道麵條煮好沒有?
And how are you supposed to tell when the noodles are done?
嘗一根
Taste one.
嗯嗯
Mmm. Mmm.
燙 燙 燙!
Hot, hot, hot!
女傭什麼時候來?
When's the maid coming?
說這話的時候 我覺得恐怕我就是女傭
As I'm saying this, I fear I'm the maid.
除了你沒人能打掃了 親愛的
No one cleans like you do, sweetie.
這太牛了
This is awesome.
親愛的?
Honey?
盡量別磨蹭 我們都非常餓了
Try not to dilly dally. We're all super hungry.
我喜歡有個爸爸的感覺
I like having a dad around.
他不是你的爸爸 小天才
He's not your dad, genius.
你答應過我態度要好的
You agreed to have a good attitude.
如果你讓他帶孩子的話我態度會好的
And I'll have a great attitude if you let him babysit,
所以我不願待在那裏一直看著這些人
so I'm not stuck here watching these guys all the time.
我們討論過這個 我不想讓他帶孩子
We went over this. I don't want him to babysit.
他為什麼只需要做你的活?
Why does he only get to do your chores?
我也想像我班上其他人一樣去游泳
I wanna go to the pool like every other kid in my class.
我不在乎!他不用帶孩子
I don't care! He's not babysitting.
因為你覺得他是個墮落者?
'Cause you think he's a pervert?
當然不是!
Of course not!
什麼是墮落者?
What's a pervert?
-沒什麼 -那我能有一個嗎?
-Nothing. -Then can I have one?
不行!他不會帶孩子的 到此為止
No! He's not babysitting. End of story.
晚安
Good night.
我什麼東西都沒得到過
I never get anything.
那麼 這是魔法開始的地方?
So, is this where the magic happens?
你甚至都記不得我是誰了
You don't even remember who I am,
還想跟我上床?
and you still wanna have sex with me?
對 很想
Yes. Very much.
所以 基本上
So, basically,
你是想和一個陌生人上床?
you wanna have sex with a complete stranger?
對 很想
Yes. Very much.
好吧 大男孩
All right, big boy.
你該懂規矩的
You know the rules.
什麼? 嗨 等等 等等 等等
What? Hey, wait, wait, wait.
我不跟你睡一起?
I'm not sleeping with you?
你需要過清靜的30天
You need 30 days clean and sober.
這是你和你的擔保人提出來的 你自己的主意 不是我的
You and your sponsor came up with that. It was your idea, not mine.
你到底在說什麼?
What are you saying?
-Boop! -你要讓我在沙發上睡覺?
-Boop! -You're gonna make me sleep on the couch?
不是 上次我們這麼做了
Nope. We tried that last time
然後你最後躺在酒櫃前面
and you ended up in the liquor cabinet.
那我睡在哪裏?
So, where am I sleeping?
就這
Here you go.
你有張小床還有其他需要的東西
You have a cot and everything.
好了
All right,
我晚上要把大門鎖起來
so I'm gonna lock up the house for the night.
如果你想上廁所的話
If you need to use the bathroom,
就用這個
here you go.
我是個小人物
I'm a nobody.
一個貧窮的 不育的 酗酒的人
A poor, sterile, drunk nobody,
還得尿在瓶子裏
who has to pee in a bottle.
但你是我的小人物啊
But you're my nobody.
好了 波比早上很早就會來接你
All right, Bobby's picking you up in the morning, bright and early.
所以你需要好好休息 好嗎?
So you need to get some rest, okay?
哦 還有 小心有熊
Oh, and watch out for bears.
那是什麼聲音
What is that noise?!
早上好
Buenos dias.
-襯衫不錯 -謝謝
-Nice shirt. -Thank you.
嗯 別灑在上面了
Yeah, don't spill on it.
這是經典款式
It's a classic and everything.
真的 它們很難買到
Seriously, they're hard to find.
好 各位
Okay, everybody.
這是裏奧
This is Leo.
布羅 布裏托
Burro. Burrito.
維托 因為他愛看
Vito, because he loves The Godfather.
這是我沒用的侄子 傑森
This is my worthless nephew, Jason.
我們叫他好運 因為他憑運氣才會有份工作
We call him Lucky, because he's lucky to have a job.
還因為我被閃電擊中過 兩次 是真的
And 'cause I got hit by lightning. Twice. For real.
我本來不該還站在這裏的
I shouldn't even be here.
對 戈多表現得好像 "哦 要命!"
Yeah. Gordo was like, "Whoa, shit!"
兄弟 你不能這麼叫我 好嗎?
Bro, you don't get to call me that, okay?
還有 別這麼自大 我以前就是你這樣
And don't be so cocky. I used to look just like you.
頭髮 腹肌 色迷迷的小眼睛
The hair, the abs, the little bedroom eyes.
你顯然不能這麼叫我
You definitely don't get to call me that.
你要給我工作至少六個月 好嗎?
You gotta work for me at least six months, okay?
歡迎 兄弟
Welcome, man.
該死 你手真沒勁兒
你之前是幹什麼的
往後點…這個可憐蛋失憶了
我知道他之前是做什麼的了 美甲
就像淑女的手一樣
Come on, we got a pool to dig. Let's go.
那個
Hey.
聽著 我確信我從來沒當過建築工人
Listen, I'm pretty sure I've never worked construction.
所以 我可能更適合跑腿
So, I might be more suited for running errands,
或者坐辦公室
or maybe some light office work.
我能做拿鬆餅的人
I could be the guy who gets the muffins.
你瞧 我是你的後盾 好嗎?
Look, I got your back, all right?
-我會好好對待你的 -好的
-I'll go easy on you. -Good.
太好了
Great.
唷!
Yo!
還有關於這些的記憶嗎 淑女?
Any of this jogging your memory, Lady Hands?
有一點吧…
等挖完這個我給你安排個很輕鬆的活
After this I got a real easy job for you.
不 我就是開個玩笑 兄弟
No, I'm just kidding, bro.
我希望我可以把他的遺體帶回家 但是…
已經被鯊魚咬得面目全非了
我兒子聞起來像肉麼?
呃...
因為 最後…
that's what we all are...我們的歸宿就是…
漢堡
你很快就會把我扔到烤架上
-我的天哪 -別說了
不 不 不
No, no, no.
新的抗生素會起作用的
我知道這是個激動人心的時刻
或許我們應該討論一下
公司的未來
沒什麼可談的
等我到地下了
你再掌權
爸爸 我很謙卑
看看吧  你一直夢想著的皇冠
這就是你想要的 是麼
對
但是不是這樣的
不是這樣的
-咖啡 -好的
-Coffee. -Yes.
謝謝
Thank you.
不客氣
You're welcome.
看看這傢伙
Look at this guy.
他什麼都有 意大利濃咖啡機
He's got it all dialed in, with his espresso machine
還有他的小甜心
and that sweet little peach.
有一天我也會成為這樣的人
That's gonna be me one day.
你什麼時候想來拜訪我都可以 兄弟
You can come over whenever you want, bro.
嗨 朋友?
Hey, guys?
你們能把泥土運到房子的另一側去嗎?
Can I get you to haul the dirt on the other side of the house?
我知道這距離更遠
I know it's longer,
但是納迪婭和我想要度過一個寧靜的早晨
but Nadia and I are trying to have a quiet morning.
對不起先生 我不會說英語
-對 -別說英語
-Right. -No speak English.
不好意思 我會跟波比說的
Sorry. I will talk to Bobby.
去吧 波比
Si. Bobby.
我喜歡這麼做
I love doing that.
發生什麼了 淑女?
失憶了肌肉也不好用了?
過來
老兄 細緻勃勃一點嘛
淑女 像個男人點嘛
上吧 夥計
再來一次 我要拍下來
他像隻猴子一樣彈進去了
記住 洗這件運動衫要用冷水
Remember, when you're washing the jersey, cold water.
聽著 慢水重洗 好嗎?
You listen. Gentle cycle. Okay?
早上好
Bueno.
嗨 尊重洗衣服的指令
Hey, respecting the wash instructions
是尊重球隊最好的方法
is the best way to respect the team.
別沾上紅色 看上去像在流血!
And no reds, they tend to bleed!
飽受煎熬 疲勞 又口渴
Tortured, tired, thirsty.
嗨 親愛的 上班第一天怎麼樣?
Hi, honey! How was your first day?
太可怕了 我的身體
Terrible. My body.
每一寸 都痛
Pain. Every. Part.
噢
Oh.
我在車子裏...
I was in the car...
於是我說 "什麼?"
And I said, "What?"
我們需要送他上醫院嗎?
Do we need to take him to the hospital?
-我說 "波比..." -不 不 不 不用
-I said, "Bobby..." -No, no, no. No.
他很好 就是需要休息
He is fine. He just needs some rest.
休息 休息吧
Rest. Rest.
哦 這就對了
Oh, that's right.
泥土...
Dirt is...
聽著 你可以稍微休息會兒
You know what? Why don't you take a few minutes,
在晚上的工作開始前
before you get started on all the things you have to do tonight?
什麼 還有工作
What? There's more?
我知道你記不清楚
I know you're having trouble remembering,
所以我給你寫了張表
so I made you a list.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我能從沙發上站起來就有鬼了
It's physically impossible for me to get off this couch.
我的腿已經廢了
I mean, my legs are no longer functioning.
聽著
Look. Look.
我很樂意 但我真的不行
I want, but I can't.
就算我能動
And even if I could move...
我也不會做這些毫無人性的工作的
I wouldn't want to do any of the vile things on this list.
背面還有呢
There's a couple more on the back, too.
我好像認識那傢伙 怎麼哪裏見過?
I know that guy. How do I know that guy?
嘿 你在Jiffy Lube工作嗎
Hey. Do you work at Jiffy Lube?
天 希望沒有
God, I hope not.
我感覺我要瘋掉了
This is gonna drive me crazy.
這是新的醬嗎 味道不一樣
Is this new sauce? It tastes different.
是啊 我加了點新東西
Yeah. I added a few things.
一些碎洋蔥 一些紅辣椒
Some chopped onion, a little red pepper
還有一點孜然
and a pinch of something called cumin.
原來那些簡直就是泔水
I couldn't bear another bowl of that tasteless slop.
我很喜歡
I like it. I like it a lot.
好多了 對吧
It's better, right?
是嗎
I don't know.
我覺得我們意面吃得夠多了
I feel like we've been having pasta too much.
或許你可以混點新東西
Maybe you should mix it up a little.
好了 我要去邊吃邊學了
Okay, I'm gonna take mine up to study.
等下清理完廚房後別忘了倒垃圾
Hey, after you clean the kitchen, don't forget, it's garbage day.
現在我知道為什麼我會失憶了
It's entirely clear to me now why I blocked out my life, Fiona.
這日子簡直沒發過
It's a hideous existence.
晚安 愛你們
Good night, you guys. I love you.
-晚安 媽媽 -愛你
-Good night, Mom. -Love you.
你在逗我嗎 你不累嗎
Oh, you gotta be kidding me. Aren't you exhausted?
誰會因為累就不想做呢
Who would use exhaustion as an excuse to not make love?
每個人都這樣
Everybody.
快回倉庫 我懂的 我也不想這樣
To the shed. I know. I know. It's hard for me, too.
今天活幹得不錯
Nice work today.
關掉 關掉
Turn it off! Turn it off!
快關掉
Turn it off!
喲 我要把這個發到朋友圈
Yo, I'm gonna post this on my Snapchat.
我會把你P成一隻河貍的兄弟
I'm gonna make you a little beaver, bro.
為什麼我們總是做些垃圾工作
How come we always get the shit jobs?
因為你就是個垃圾工人
Because you're unskilled laborers!
自由國度 不是免費午餐國度
Land of the free, no land of the free lunch.
快幹活吧
你真是個天才
Okay. You are a genius.
我昨晚睡了整整七個小時
I got seven hours of sleep last night,
猜猜他晚飯做了什麼
and guess what he's making for dinner?
雞肉串 椰子飯
Chicken skewers, coconut rice.
哇 我也想要一個假丈夫
Aw, I want a fake husband.
謝謝你 謝謝你
Thank you. Thank you.
我這周學的比我之前一個月學的還多
I got more studying done this week than I have in months.
那我下次讓你幫我去犯罪
Maybe next time I ask you to commit a crime,
你應該不會反對吧
you won't fight me on it.
不知道為什麼
我感覺
我現在的生活不是我自己的
我的意思是
看看這傢伙的豪宅
海景豪宅
我感覺這應該是我的生活
是 你應該過比爾·蓋茨或者卡洛斯·斯利姆那樣生活。
有豪宅和私人飛機
哥們 我也是這麼想的
這就是買彩票的原因
我會在每週五的同一時間 買同一注彩票
12-21-45 我的幸運數字
估計教父買橘子被槍殺的那天
你才能中獎
你還沒懂
我感覺有些事兒不對勁
有時候我看我老婆
對她毫無印象
跟你講
你是沒見過沙利文高中時候的樣子
她那時候特別火爆
現在 我簡直不敢認她了
她真變醜了
相信我 她也不想這樣的
他這麼說的嘛
不是 我是認真的
我感覺我們不是真正的夫妻
我都不知道我們多久沒有性生活了
真的 我不知道
你知道我上次跟我老婆做愛是什麼時候麼
我女兒出生前九個月
她剛三歲
-快離他遠點 -他看著我們呢
兄弟 你可真幸運能夠失憶
Bro, you're lucky you have amnesia.
我還記得我以前覺得我侄子
I remember when I thought my nephew
以後真能有點出息
was actually gonna do something with his life.
搞音樂難道就沒出息了 我是個音樂家
Music is something. I'm an artist.
你現在還睡我沙發呢 兄弟
You're sleeping on my couch, bro.
等我拿了格萊美
Yeah, well, that tune's gonna change
你那口氣就會變了
when I thank you at the Grammys, Gordo.
-是嗎 -沒錯
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
你最好趕快 知道為什麼嗎
You better pick it up, dawg. You know what I'm saying?
因為新陳代謝30歲左右就慢下來了
'Cause the Diaz metabolism slows down around 30.
看到這個了沒
See this right here?
這可不會幫你上音樂榜
It's not gonna get you on the charts, dawg.
都是些我不想做的工作
I got some work I don't feel like doing.
那你還帶那頂帽子幹嘛
Why do you even wear that hard hat, man?
You know I can take you!
這事兒就像
我感覺我就是個錢包
淑女手
你就是個錢包
還不是個稱職的錢包
可悲啊
哥們 我們都是這麼覺著的
-真假? -當然了
-你們所有人都這麼覺得? -所有人
歡迎加入我們
聽著 淑女手 你很幸運
有穩定的工作
一個受得了你廢話的妻子 三個漂亮健康的女兒
等他講完叫醒我行麼?
別像個混蛋一樣
記住考利昂老頭跟你說什麼了麼
像個男人一樣
"Act like a man."
Act like a man.
像個男人一樣
Act like a man!
-明天見 博迪 -好的 兄弟
-See you tomorrow, Bobby. -Okay, brother.
嘿 別告訴Theresa雞肉芝士的事
Hey, remember, don't tell Theresa about the chicken parm.
嘿
Hey.
我給你帶了點東西
I got you something.
冰凍酸奶
Frozen yogurt.
就像以前在Playa的時候
Like the old days on the Playa.
-哪 -Playa Tortugas
-What? -On the Playa Tortugas.
哦 哦
Oh, oh.
沒錯 那裏的日落
Right. Yeah, the sunsets.
-對 -是啊 真是好日子
-Yeah. -Yes. Good times.
我忘記我們喜歡什麼口味了
I couldn't remember which flavors we liked,
所以我每種都弄了些
so I got an assortment.
謝謝 這真的
Thanks. This was
很好
really nice of you.
我知道我最近不太好相處
I know I haven't been the easiest to live with lately,
但我會努力的
but I'm gonna try a little harder.
我說不準會有多努力 但夠我自己驚訝的了
I can't promise a lot harder, but maybe I'll surprise myself.
繼續努力
Well, keep doing this.
下次可以帶點配料
Maybe next time, bring some toppings.
嗯嗯
Mmm.
芒果 我很喜歡芒果
Mango. I love mango.
我以前也喜歡芒果嗎
Have I always loved mango?
據我所知是的
As long as I've known you.
啊 是啊
Ah, yes.
當我們年輕時
When we were young
手控制不住在對方身上亂摸的時候
and couldn't keep our hands off each other.
拒絕
No.
好的
Okay.
我去倉庫待著了
Well... I'll be in my shed.
試著保持樂觀
Trying to have a good attitude.
就我和蜘蛛
Just me and the spiders.
噢
Oh.
還有我的廁所
Forgot my bathroom.
喲
Whew. Whew!
爸爸 我現在過得好痛苦
記得我剛去紐約
想成為一名音樂會大提琴演奏家的時候
你很生氣 打斷了我
我已經原諒你了
基本原諒了
但是萊昂納多支持我
他飛去紐約
幫我收拾我的公寓
他是唯一一個相信我有天分的人
他一直相信我
他死的太突然了
瑪格達對細節描述的含含糊糊的
我需要萊昂納多·黑山的死亡證明
I'm calling to get a death certificate for Leonardo Montenegro.
他前幾周死於鯊魚攻擊
He died a couple of weeks ago in a shark attack.
沒錯 來自一隻鯊魚的攻擊
Yes. An attack by a shark fish?
我覺得我沒說錯
I think I'm saying that correctly.
我的老天爺 這東西有多重
九十磅
真殘忍
他們應該生產點人能扛得動
可能這樣是為了 一個袋子省三美分吧
黑山
貪婪的混蛋
嘿 今天發工資
到時候了
布裏托
謝謝老闆
這是你的 裏奧
客戶要求我們早點離開 這樣他就可以
做個按摩或者數數錢什麼的
嘿 嘿 小心
Hey! Hey! Watch out!
你盯著看什麼呢
不應該啊 但是感覺這是我收到的第一張支票
別弄丟了 淑女手
-謝謝 Bobby -你應得的 兄弟
-Thanks, Bobby. -You got it, bro.
-好了 -嘿
-All right. -Hey!
-嘿 -嘿 親愛的
-Hey! -Hey, sweetie!
好
噢 記住哈塞爾貝克
Oi, remember Hasselbeck.
他比人們講的還要多變
He's way more mobile than people give him credit for.
嘿
Hey.
-你怎麼不騎呢 -有這兩個穩定輪在沒意思
-Why aren't you riding? -It's no fun with training wheels.
我沒教過你騎車嗎
I never taught you to ride a bike?
沒事的 有些爸爸就是太忙
It's okay. Some dads can't be around that much.
不 不行
No, it's not okay.
我馬上就教你
I'm gonna fix this. Right now.
我先把這些拿進去 好吧
Let me just put this away. Okay?
你在這幹嘛
What are you doing here?
今天工作很早就結束了
They got us working bankers' hours today.
所以早回來了
Whatever those are.
所以 你能看著這些傢伙
So then it's cool if you watch those guys,
讓我去游泳嗎
so I can go to the pool?
沒問題
Yeah, sure. Why not?
謝謝 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
-嘿 老媽 -你肯定會很吃驚的
-Hey, Mom. -You're gonna be blown away.
現代高級雜誌說我的表演很搶眼
Modern Senior magazine said my performance stole the show.
我還上了聖猶大健康簡報封面的特寫
And the Saint Jude wellness newsletter featured me on the cover.
是啊 你不幫我看小孩的事完全洗白了呢
That certainly justifies leaving me without childcare.
人生短暫 凱特
Life's short, Kate.
你要做能讓你開心的事
You gotta do what makes you happy.
我不想因為沒做自己想做的事情
I don't wanna have regrets
而有遺憾
just because I didn't do what I wanted to do.
你以後會理解的 親愛的
You'll understand someday, honey.
天吶 我要掛了 媽
Shit! I gotta go, Mom.
大家都再看
Everyone's looking.
我不在意
I don't care!
我拜託你了一個月 就讓你照看下你的妹妹們
I asked you for one month, just watch your sisters.
而且我們基本不瞭解那個人
And we don't even know anything about this guy.
是誰的錯 又不是我把他帶到家裏來的
Whose fault is that? I didn't bring him into the house.
這不是重點
That's not the point.
兩分鐘後我來告訴你為什麼
And I'll tell you why in two minutes.
這事還沒完
We're not done talking about this!
因為你 他們的披薩都冷掉了
And because of you, their pizza was cold
只給了我這麼點小費
and they gave me a lousy tip.
可能你小費拿得少是因為你自己太慢
Maybe you got a bad tip because you run like a duck.
你最好祈禱沒什麼事發生
You better hope everything's okay.
我討厭這整件事情 真的很蠢
I hate this. I hate this whole thing. It's so stupid.
我愛海鷹隊
I love the Seahawks!
我們的隊伍剛把球帶過了終點線
Our team just ran the ball to the finish line.
是球門區 我們剛說過了
The end zone. We've been over this.
對對 觸地得分
Oh, right. Touchdown.
記憶慢慢在恢復
It's coming back slowly.
看吧 媽 一切都好 沒人死
See, Mom, everything's fine. No one died.
凱特 我找了些人幫忙修理屋頂的漏水
Oh, and, Kate, I got some of the guys to help me fix that leak in the roof.
你打開了這些盒子嗎
And you unpacked the boxes?
是 是 我找到了這些枕頭
Oh, yeah, yeah. And I found these pillows.
這沙發需要些亮色
The couch needed a splash of color.
什麼
What?
一點點的 鳥築起了它的巢 這是法語
"Little by little, the bird builds its nest." It's French.
等等 我還說法語
Wait. I speak French.
為什麼我會說法語
Why do I speak French?
額
Uh...
你是個導遊
Well, you were a tour guide,
眾所周知 巴黎人喜歡昆卡
and it's well-known that Parisians love Cancun.
因為那裏的薯條和辣醬 還有西班牙舞
For it's chips and salsa and its flamenco dancers.
非常感謝你毫無意義的羞辱
Thanks for humiliating me for nothing.
嘿 我們約好了的 你自己沒有遵守
Hey! Hey, we had a deal, and you didn't stick to it.
你被禁足了
You're grounded.
誰還在乎 我基本就是這裏的囚犯
Who cares? I'm basically a prisoner here anyway!
-禁足一星期 -凱特凱特 嘿
-For a week! -Kate, Kate, Kate. Hey.
我們能談談嗎
Can I talk to you for a sec?
聽著 你知道13歲的時候是個什麼感覺
Okay, listen, you remember what it's like to be 13.
我不知道 但你應該知道
I don't, but you probably do.
你在說什麼
What are you getting at?
不准用手機
And no phone!
嘿 嘿 我就是覺得你可能有點...
Hey, hey, I just think maybe you're being...
可能 對她太嚴厲了
I don't know, a little hard on her.
不要管我怎麼養我的小孩
Don't tell me how to raise my kids.
"你的小孩"
"Your kids"?
嘿 聽著
Hey. Listen.
不要覺得因為這些孩子不是我的種
Just because those girls were not conceived with my seed,
我就不是她們的父親或一個男人
doesn't make me any less their father or a man.
當然不是 我只是...
Of course not. I just...
我還沒說完
I'm not done.
我為這個家庭當牛做馬
All I do is work and work and slave for this family.
可能我沒讓大家過上奢華的好日子
I may not have put us in the lap of luxury,
但我依然是那個養家餬口的人
but I'm a provider.
你剛說的真的是很過分
What you said was a low blow.
不公平 很傷人 很過分
An unfair and hurtful low blow.
-親愛的 我... -很過分
-Honey, I... -Low blow.
我要透會兒氣
I need some air.
裏奧!
Leo!
等我看下他們的分數先
Right after I check the score.
好極了
And it is good!
-我們輸了 -亞利桑那隊的驚人勝利
-We lost. -A stunning win for Arizona.
開心了吧
I hope you're happy.
-你去哪 -不知道
-Where are you going? -I don't know.
但不是因為我失憶了
And not because I don't remember, hmm?
因為我不知道
Because I don't know.
我叫裏奧 我是個酒鬼
My name is Leo and I'm an alcoholic.
嗨 裏奧
Hi, Leo.
說實話 我不太記得我喝酒的那些時候了
To be honest, I don't really remember my drinking days.
-是啊 -理解
-Yep. -Been there.
晚上我和我老婆吵架了
I got in a fight with my wife tonight.
我在一家酒吧門口站了20分鐘
I stood outside a bar for 20 minutes.
就差這麼點 這麼點我就進去了
I came this close. This...
但... 現在我在這了
But here I am.
-多來幾次 -每天一次
-Keep coming back. -One day at a time.
便血 便血 便血
♪ Bloody stools Bloody stools, bloody stools
抗血小板 便血
♪ Antiplatelet, bloody stools ♪
操
Holy shit!
萊昂納多黑山
Leonardo Montenegro.
對 他前幾周在你那區被鯊魚咬死了
Yeah, he was murdered by a shark in your district several weeks ago.
抱歉 女士
Sorry, ma'am.
這裏已經四年沒有鯊魚襲擊的案件了
Haven't had a shark attack around here in four years.
是嗎
Really?
你不需要和其他警局核對一下嗎
Don't you have to check with other police stations?
不需要 女士 我向你保證
Lady, I promise you,
如果有人聽到鯊魚襲擊的消息
if anyone's gonna hear about a shark attack,
那一定是我
it's gonna be me.
祝你好運
Good luck to you.
嗯
Hmm.
-嗨  -嗨
-Hey. -Hey.
嗯
Um...
今晚很抱歉
Sorry about tonight.
該道歉的應該是我
I'm the one who should apologize.
不 我真的應該心胸寬闊點
No, I really need to keep my side of the street clean
你知道 培養一顆感恩的心態
and, you know, cultivate an attitude of gratitude.
我反應有點過激了 我跟艾米麗談過了 不再限制她自由
I overreacted. I talked to Emily and ungrounded her.
我只是對這個考試太緊張了
I'm just so stressed out about this test.
嗯 你一直都很努力學習
Well, you've been working so hard and...
我來吧
I got it.
我也一直在想怎麼才能幫助你
And I've been thinking how I can help.
所以我和特麗薩談過
So I talked to Theresa
她和我都能接受你的一些變化
and she's okay with me picking up a few of your shifts.
-真的 你為了我這麼做  -是的
-Really? You'd do that for me? -Yeah.
我也不是無私
I'm not being selfless.
我只是很少想到我自己
I'm just thinking of myself less.
你喜歡在裏面加牛奶 對吧
You like it with milk, right?
再加點糖
And a little sugar.
星期天我會帶一整天孩子 這樣你就可以學習
Oh, and I'll take the kids all day Sunday so you can study.
你一個人 我不能讓
By yourself? I can't let...
實際上 這樣非常棒
Actually, that would be amazing.
那就好
Great.
我一直在想我應該 喔
I was also thinking that I should... Oh! Ah!
鋒利的刀子 血 血 好多血
Sharp knife. Blood. Blood. Lots of blood.
-我討厭血  -沒事
-I do not like blood. -All right.
沒事 放鬆 你沒事的
All right, take it easy. You're okay.
-讓我看看 讓我看看 -救我
-Let me see, let me see. -Help.
我要用水沖一下
I'm just gonna wash it off.
我感覺頭暈 我要暈倒了
Feeling queasy. Gonna faint.
不 你不會暈倒的
No. You're not gonna faint.
-我現在很暈  -不會
-I'm fainting. -No.
房子在轉
The room is spinning.
沒事 你在那兒坐會
All right, let's just sit you down over here.
情況嚴重嗎
How bad is it?
我應該去醫院嗎 我需要止血帶嗎
Should I go to the hospital? Do I need a tourniquet?
放鬆 你和專業的醫生在一起呢
Relax. You are with a trained professional.
-我需要縫針嗎 -不需要
-Do I need stitches? -No.
快救我 我要失血而亡了
Please help me. I'm bleeding to death.
哦 天哪 傷口真的很深
Oh, God! It's really deep.
你到底在做什麼呀
What the hell are you doing?
清理傷口 天哪 你真像個小孩子
Cleaning the cut. My God, you're such a baby!
我知道怎麼做
I got this.
關於這個我上了一整節課
I took a whole class on it.
包紮傷口
Dressing wounds?
護理歇斯底里的病人
Dealing with hysterical patients.
好
All right.
好了
Okay.
這裏
There.
你很擅長臨床護理
You have very good bedside manner.
-你這樣認為嗎  -是的
-You think so? -Yeah.
有時候我擔心我會做不好
Sometimes I worry about that.
不 不 你很有天賦
No. No, you're a natural.
好了 可以了 完好如新
All right. There you go. Good as new.
嗯
Well, um...
我想我該讓你學習了
I guess I'll let you study.
謝謝你如此照料我
Thanks for taking such good care of me.
好的
Okay.
晚安
Good night.
等一下
Wait.
你可以睡裏面 樓梯下的沙發上
You can sleep inside. Downstairs, on the couch.
你讓我非常高興
You've made me very happy.
凱特琳娜怎麼了?
What happened to Catalina?
她的孩子沒了
She lost the baby.
她的孩子沒了?
She lost it?
現在阿圖爾絕不會和她結婚了
Now Arturo will never marry her.
當然不會 絕不會
Of course not. Never.
遊玩結束之後我們會來接你 嗯
We'll pick you up after the game, hmm?
不客氣
You're welcome!
為什麼我們不能游泳
Why can't we go swimming?
我們要給你姐姐一點空間
We're giving your sister a little space.
太多空間了
Too much space.
我們給她太多空間了
We're giving her too much space.
大家都看著呢
Everyone's watching.
我不管
I don't care!
我不需要聽你的 你又不是我真正的爸爸
I don't have to listen to you. You're not even my real dad.
什麼 你媽媽告訴你的
What? Your mother told you?
我仍然不能讓你毀掉你的生活
Well, I'm still not letting you throw your life away
因為那些性狂 卷髮惡狼
for some sex-crazed, curly-haired wolf.
那個男孩只想做一件事 就只有一件事
That boy wants one thing and one thing only.
他是個同性戀
He's gay.
好吧 是另一件事
Okay. One different thing.
你在做什麼 為什麼你要哭
What are you doing? Why are you crying?
因為我很痛苦
Because I'm miserable.
你很痛苦
You are?
是的
Yeah.
我曾在波特蘭很受歡迎
I was really popular in Portland,
在這裏 每個人都有自己的團體 就我不在他們裏面
and here everyone's on group texts that I'm not a part of.
這個男孩是我喜歡的西班牙課上的同學
And there's this boy in my Spanish class that I like,
但是他不知道我的存在
but he doesn't know that I exist.
他是這裏救生員的朋友 就是
And he's friends with the lifeguard here and that's...
等一下 你在上西班牙語課
Wait, you're taking Spanish?
非常好
Muy bien.
你的發音很自然
Your pronunciation is very natural.
我的意思是 發「R」音的時候你需要捲舌I mean, you still need to roll the "R's".
什麼
What?
說一下
Say it.
-你必須  -爸爸  -好的 好的
-You have to...   -Dad!  -Okay, okay.
他怎麼會不知道你的存在呢
How could he not know you exist?
你是一個多麼美麗 聰慧 有思想的女生
You're a beautiful, smart, thoughtful young woman.
他能成為你的男朋友應該是他的榮幸
He'd be lucky to be your boyfriend.
但是你還太年輕 去交男朋友了
But you're way too young for a boyfriend.
他們都應該為能成為你的男朋友感到榮幸
They'd all be lucky to be your boyfriend.
每個人都應該跪著求著做你男朋友
Every boy here should beg to be your boyfriend.
但是我禁止 我不許
But I forbid it. I forbid it!
我知道我在地圖上到處都是
I know I'm all over the map. It's just...
有一個女兒會很糾結
It's very confusing having a daughter.
我不會做傻事的 好吧
Look. I'm not gonna do anything stupid. All right?
去好好玩吧
Go have fun.
藍隊52號 離開熱門路線
Blue 52. Hot route left.
耶 耶
Yes! Yes!
跑 跑 跑 很棒 很棒 很棒
Go, go, go. Yes! Yes! Yes!
跑 跑 跑 耶
Go! Go! Go! Yes!
噢唔
Woo-hoo!
-耶  -耶
-Yeah! -Yeah!
-我們做到了 -這是我女兒
-Go team! Yeah, we did it! -That's my daughter.
我們知道
We know.
第二次進球
Second touchdown.
我們贏了 事實上
We're winning, actually.
耶 我們踢到了他們的屁股
Yeah, we kicked their butts!
-非常感謝你拯救了我 -啊哦
-Thanks for rescuing me. -Ah.
我腦子裏一片混亂
My mind was turning into mush.
嗨 莫莉
Hey, Molly!
你什麼時候脫離三輪車的
When did you learn how to ride without training wheels?
爸爸教我的
Dad taught me.
她只摔過一次哦
She only fell once.
加速 加速 加速
Faster! Faster! Faster!
加油 加油 加油 耶
Come on, come on, come on! Yes, yes, yes!
噢唔
Whoo!
我應該怎樣擺脫大腦凍結
So how do I get rid of the brain freeze?
-像這樣  -這樣
-Go like this. -Like this?
嗯
Mmm.
你會離開我們嗎
Are you gonna leave us?
你在說什麼 當然不會 我是你的爸爸
What do you mean? Of course not. I'm your dad.
有時候爸爸是會離開的
Sometimes dads leave.
好的 可能別人會 但我哪兒也不去
Well, I guess maybe they do, but I'm not going anywhere.
你把我困住了
You're stuck with me.
謝謝
Thank you.
A體重突增 B腹部瘙癢
"A. Sudden weight gain. B. Abdominal itch.
C大便出血 D光
"C. Bloody stools. D. Light..."
大便出血
Bloody stools.
哎 爸爸
我還好
我的病都好了.
你仍然在治療中
我剛剛自己上廁所了
你敢相信嗎?這個庸醫說的竟然是對的
我三十年來一直都是對的
爸爸
我太開心了
你可以回撥電話 公司仍然給你
或許我一開始就應該把它給你
我受寵若驚啊 爸比
科林 你當時和瑪格達萊娜一起嗎
Colin, were you with Magdalena
當她確認我哥屍體的時候
when she identified my brother's body?
不 夫人 她堅持要自己處理這件事
No, ma'am, she was quite insistent on handling the matter herself.
你暗示什麼
Are you insinuating?
我應該暗示什麼
Should I be insinuating?
在你回答之前 記得我是蘇格蘭人
And before you answer that, remember I'm Scottish.
我可以這樣重複一整天
I can do this all day long.
嗨 所以 考試怎麼樣
Hey! So, the test?
有兩道題我都不記得了 但至少都結束了
There was a couple that I blanked on, but at least it's over.
現在我不需要維持這個瘋狂的謊言了
Now I don't have to keep up this insane lie.
你確定你不再過兩周 再告訴他
Are you sure you don't wanna wait a couple of weeks before you tell him?
我的意思是 這麼好的幫助很難找到的
I mean, good help is hard to find.
是的 確實 孩子們也開始喜歡他了
Yeah, totally. And the guys are really starting to like him, too.
不 不 很公平 他在償還他的債務
No. No. Fair is fair. He has paid his debt.
我已經讓他吃夠苦了
I have tortured him long enough.
好的
Okay.
你又會非常討厭做家務的
You're really gonna hate doing your own laundry again.
夥伴們
Guys...
我感到很緊張
I feel pretty nervous.
我怕會嚇到他
I think he's gonna freak out.
嚇到他
Freak out?
凱特 你要告訴一個挖溝渠的工人 他是一個億萬富翁
Kate, you're telling a ditch digger he's a billionaire, you know.
我覺得他很快會接受的
I'm pretty sure he's gonna be okay with it.
是的
Yeah.
嗨
Hey.
嗯 我需要告訴你
Uh, I need to talk to you.
嗯 怎麼了
Yeah. What's up?
我必須承認一件事 但我不知道從哪說起
I have to confess something, and I don't know where to start.
不管是什麼
Well, whatever it is,
我覺得應該不是什麼大事
I'm sure it's not that big of a deal.
-是很大的事  -是嗎
-It's pretty big. -Yeah?
並且聽起來會很瘋狂
And this is gonna sound crazy.
可能又有趣又瘋狂或者很瘋狂很瘋狂
Maybe funny-crazy or crazy-crazy.
但是我做了一件很糟糕的事
But I did something terrible.
等一下
Hold that thought.
孩子們
Girls!
晚飯做好了
Dinner's ready!
好 都坐下吧
Yeah. Sit down, please.
-小心 它很燙  -好香
-Be careful, it's hot. -It smells so good.
-我覺得味道應該不錯  -看起來很不錯
-I hope it tastes good. -It looks so good.
用勺子 嗯
Use a spoon. Mmm.
好
So...
你想要承認什麼糟糕的事
What's this awful thing you need to confess?
我
I...
沒事 我是你丈夫 你什麼事都可以告訴我
Come on, I'm your husband. You can tell me anything.
我忘記今天是我們的結婚紀念日了
I forgot it's our anniversary.
真的嗎
Really?
今天
Today?
週年快樂
Happy anniversary!
我們要出去度過
We're going out!
你們很棒
You guys are really good.
謝謝 兄弟 告訴我叔
Thanks, bro. Tell my uncle.
十五年
Fifteen years.
很多夫婦都不會走這麼久
A lot of couples don't make it that long.
是的
Yeah.
謝謝你一直支持著我
Thanks for sticking with me.
我知道我並沒有減輕負擔
I know I haven't made things easy.
-這外面很美  -是很美
-It's pretty out here. -Beautiful.
你知道輪船像這樣鳴叫三聲代表什麼意思嗎
Do you know what it means when a ship honks three times like that?
有人告訴過我 但我忘記了
Someone told me once, but I forgot.
我知道
Yes, I do.
這是一個很古老的西班牙傳說
It's based on an old, Spanish legend.
是的
Yeah.
而且 確實很浪漫
Very romantic, by the way.
從前有一個很窮的女僕 叫凱特麗娜
You see, there was a poor housemaid named Catalina.
她非常漂亮 吸引了殖民地州長兒子阿圖羅的注意
She was very pretty and caught the eye of the colonial governor's son, Arturo.
等一下 你什麼都不記得
Okay, wait. You don't remember anything,
你還會記得這個
yet you remember this?
這是個很有名的傳說
It's a very famous legend.
然後 他們相愛了
So, they fell in love.
當然
Of course.
但是阿圖羅的父親不讓他們在一起
But Arturo's father forbade it.
他不能讓他的兒子圍繞在一個平民身邊
He couldn't have his only son running around with a commoner.
所以 他命令阿圖羅回西班牙 他也這麼做了
So, he ordered Arturo to return to Spain, which he did.
但在沒向凱特麗娜承諾前
But not before promising Catalina
他會回來 並且給她發信號
he'd come back and signal for her
三聲長鳴
with three long blasts.
就像你剛剛聽到的一樣
Just like you heard.
這聽起來很像廚房員工看的一個節目
This sounds suspiciously like one of the shows the kitchen guys watch.
-我不知道你在說什麼  -嗯嗯
-I have no idea what you're talking about. -Uh-huh.
不管怎樣 一年後 一切都按計劃進行著
Anyway, a year later, everything went as planned.
她游出去了 但霧太濃
She swam out, but the fog was too thick.
他呼喊著 凱特麗娜 凱特麗娜
He called out, "Catalina! Catalina!"
她回應 阿圖羅 阿圖羅
She yelled back, "Arturo! Arturo!"
隨後 他也跳進了水裏
And with that, he dove into the water.
他們重聚了
They reunited,
凱特麗娜 她在這之前
and Catalina, who, up until that point,
一直在抗拒他
had been resisting him
因為一些她不得不學習的測試
because of some test she had to study for,
最終另他吻了她
finally let him kiss her.
嗯
Hmm.
哦 現在我記起來了
Oh. Now I remember.
三聲鳴笛意味著船將要逆行
Three honks means a boat's about to go in reverse.
好吧
Okay.
也許 確實
Maybe. Factually.
但是
But I...
一直這麼美好嗎
Was it always this good?
每次和你都像是第一次
Every time with you is like the first time.
看看這個 我們造的
Look at this thing. We built it.
你的第一個游泳池 兄弟
Your first pool, bro.
幹得好
Good job.
嘿 看看你 你有了一雙工人的手
Hey, look at you, you got working man hands now.
是啊
Yeah!
是的
Yes, I do!
真不錯
That's good.
這場比賽從拉普湯姆林森開始
Take that play, get off the block there by Laken Tomlinson.
他會成為防禦性的最佳球員 我向你保證
This guy will be a defensive MVP one day, I guarantee you.
爸爸 什麼是變態
Dad, what's a pervert?
嗯..
Um...
就是 呃
Well, uh...
當一個男人
When a man
有一個
has a van...
凱特
Kate!
莫莉有個問題
Molly has a question for you.
它們為何這麼久
What is taking them so long?
你要放鬆下嗎
Would you relax?
他們說了他們會在2點以後公佈結果
They said they were gonna post the results after 2:00 p.m.
好的 中場休息
All right. Halftime.
我要吃午飯了
I'm getting lunch.
哦等下 我的清單在哪
Oh, wait. Where's my list?
這裏
Here.
麼 再見
Mmm... Ciao.
等下 嘿 我忘了
Wait! Hey, I forgot.
親愛的
Honey!
帶點捲心菜沙拉 好嗎 還有薯片
Get coleslaw, okay? And maybe some potato chips.
好 知道了
Okay, got it.
寫下來 我知道你 你會忘的
Write it down. I know you. You're gonna forget.
還有曲奇 我想要曲奇
And get cookies. I want cookies.
曲奇
Cookies.
筆
Pen.
凱特
Kate!
怎麼了
What's the matter?
我不知道 我只是在想
I don't know. I was just wondering
一個不育男性的妻子
what the wife on an infertile man would be doing
要一條帶螺紋的安全套做什麼
with a strip of ribbed, reservoir-tipped Trojans?
好吧
Okay...
這不是你想的那樣
This is not what you think.
這沒什麼
It's nothing.
沒什麼? 我們發過誓的
Nothing? We made a vow.
一個神聖的誓言 我遵守了 我想
A sacred vow, which I kept, I think.
別以為我沒有機會
And don't assume I didn't have opportunities,
我有過
because I did.
很多很多 可能
Lots and lots of them. Probably.
這是很傻的
This is nuts.
你知道嗎 我很開心
You know what, I'm glad.
我很高興你找到了這些
I'm glad you found these,
因為我嘗試想一種方式告訴你
because I have been trying to think of a way to tell you this.
你和我
You and I...
我們沒有真的結婚
We're not really married.
我沒有讓你幸福嗎
Have I not made you happy?
不是 但這不是重點
Yes, but that's not the point.
我不是你的妻子
I'm not your wife.
這些孩子 他們不是你的孩子
Those kids in there,
they're not your children.
哦 又來了
Oh, this again.
不小的打擊
Low blow.
好吧 過來
All right, come on. Come on!
女孩們
Girls?
女孩們 我剛告訴了他真相 我也希望你們告訴他
Girls, I just told him the truth, and I want you to tell him, too.
繼續 告訴他
Go ahead, tell him.
告訴他什麼
Tell him what?
告訴他 他不是你們的爸爸
Tell him he's not your dad.
但他是我們的爸爸
But he is our dad?
不 別告訴他我告訴你們的
No, don't tell him what I told you to tell him.
告訴他真相 艾米莉
Tell him what really happened. Emily?
他喝醉了 停在沙灘上
He got drunk and blacked out on the beach.
我們很擔憂 我不能睡
We were really worried. I couldn't sleep.
不 見鬼 告訴他真相
No, damn it! Tell him the truth!
別這樣對我的三個火槍手說話
Don't you speak to my three musketeers like that.
我知道了
I've had it.
你們在做什麼
What do you think you're doing?
-我們喜歡他 -我們想要留住他
-We like him. -We want to keep him.
你們不能留住他 他不屬於你們
You can't keep him. He doesn't belong to you.
他也不屬於你 但這並沒有阻攔你
He didn't belong to you, either, but that didn't stop you.
-你們知道我有我的原因 -我們也有
-You know I have my reasons. -So do we.
裏奧 聽著 你們 那些避孕套不是凱特的
Leo, listen. Look, look, look.
Those condoms aren't Kate's.
他們是我的
They're mine.
別為她解釋
Don't cover for her.
不 我沒有 她在為我解釋
No, I'm not. She's covering for me.
是的 我是那個和顧客睡覺的人
Yeah. I'm the one sleeping with the customers.
真的嗎
Really?
我有問題 裏奧 我有性癮
I have a problem, Leo. I'm obsessed with sex.
怎麼可能
Come on.
我有性癮 這是真的
I'm a sex addict! It's a real thing.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
凱特 我坦白了
Kate! I confessed.
你不用再為我說謊了
You don't have to lie for me anymore.
我會得到我要的幫助
I can finally get the help I need.
現在不用擔心 你不用告訴鮑比
Now, don't worry. You don't have to tell Bobby.
我會告訴他
I'll tell him.
你討厭我嗎
Do you hate me?
當然不
Of course not.
人性有弱點
I know the flesh is weak.
嘿 一天一次 好嗎
Hey, one day at a time. Hmm?
好 一天一次
Yeah, one day at a time.
我很抱歉 我沒有相信你
I'm so sorry I didn't trust you.
這真的嚇到我了
That really scared me.
好像我的一生都是個謊言
It was like my whole life was a lie.
快來 他們回到場上了
Come on, they're back on the field!
嘿 後半場要開始了
Hey. Second half's about to start.
介意我走嗎
Mind doing the sandwich run?
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
我不能永遠保持下去
I can't keep this up forever.
為什麼不能
Why not?
我知道你們的關係有些不傳統
Okay, look, I know your relationship's a little unconventional.
但誰的不是呢 你們在一起很好
But whose isn't? You guys are good together.
別再抗爭了
Stop fighting it.
我要告訴你一件事
I'll tell you one thing.
不論是否偽裝 鮑比作為拉丁人不喜歡被欺騙
Pretend or not, Bobby's Latin ego is not gonna like being cheated on.
-凱特 -天哪
-Kate! -Shit.
他們告訴了他
They told him.
你通過了 你是一個護士
You passed! You're a nurse!
祝賀你 媽媽
Congratulations, Mom!
-徒步旅行 -我們一起去吧
-Hike! -Let's do this.
-嘿 戈爾戈 -嘿
-Hey, Gordo. -Hey.
你還好嗎
You okay?
哈?哦
Huh? Oh.
你知道的 我好多了
Yeah, well, you know, I've been better.
好
Yeah.
但這是我們需要的叫醒鬧鈴
But this is the wake-up call we needed.
我不用像我應該的那樣關注她的需要
I wasn't as attentive to her needs as I should have been.
你知道 我可以情感上疏遠一些 兄弟
You know, I can be emotionally remote, bro.
我們將要開始夫妻治療
We're starting couples therapy.
-不錯 -是啊
-Oh, good. -Yeah.
不管你做什麼 你知道的 不要
Just, whatever you do, you know, don't...
我很抱歉 把凱特視為理所當然 因為
I'm sorry, take Kate for granted. Because...
你看 我知道我們可以有一點大男子主義
Look, I know we can be
a little machista.
-這是我們的方法 對 -你知道?
-It's our way. Yeah. -You know?
但你的敏感和誠實感動了我
But your vulnerability and honesty really touches me.
你欠我的
You owe me.
我知道
I know.
哦 這是聖誕卡
Oh, yeah, this is a Christmas card.
天哪 好冷
Oh, God, it's cold!
我抓住你了
I got you!
那是他 那個鬥雞的人
That's him. The chicken fight guy.
我的天啊!
My God!
萊昂納多 你總是支持我的音樂夢想
Leonardo, you always supported my musical dreams.
比如你曾說過 當上帝給了你天賦
Like you said, "When God gives you a gift...
使用它是你的責任
it's your responsibility to use it."
這首歌是給你的 這是一首巴赫的歌
This is for you. It's Bach.
就在這裏 那命中注定的一天...
It was here, that fateful night...
當萊昂納多勇敢的
when Leonardo bravely fought
和野鯊戰鬥 然後死去
the savage shark and perished.
今天 他的遺骨可以...
Today, his remains can...
索菲亞 可以了 謝謝你親愛的
Sofia, that's enough. Thank you, my dear.
今天他的遺骨可以回到身體缺失的那一部分中
Today his remains can join the rest of his body.
讓我們每個人都抓起一把我們最愛的萊昂納多...
Let's each take a handful of our beloved Leonardo...
和他最後道個別
and say our final goodbyes.
抓住骨灰 抱歉
Hold the ashes! Sorry, sorry.
這是在20分鐘前拍的
This was taken 20 minutes ago.
-萊昂納多嗎 -什麼
-Leonardo? -What?
是萊昂納多
It's Leonardo!
他還活著!萊昂納多還活著!
He's alive! Leonardo's alive!
他還活著!
He's alive!
嘿 你們
Hey, you guys! You guys!
在我切蛋糕前
Before I cut the cake,
我想感謝你們在都這裏
I just want to thank you all for being here.
沒有你們我無法通過測驗
I could not have passed the test without you all.
-凱特護士 -凱特護士
-Nurse Kate! -Nurse Kate!
尤其是你 裏奧
Especially you, Leo.
他做飯 他打掃
He cooked, he cleaned.
他做兩份工作 他讓我笑
He worked two jobs, he kept me laughing.
如果你們之前沒有嘗過這個餡餅
And if you haven't tried the empanadas yet,
他們很美味 他做的
they are delicious.He made them.
都吃光了!
They're gone!
什麼 寶寶
What, babe?
他很美味 兄弟
They're delicious, bro.
謝謝你 我的愛人
你改變了我的生活
稍等
Wait, wait, wait.
我也想說點什麼
I want to say something, too.
我的意思是看著這張臉
I mean, look at this face.
-看著這張臉 -哦
-Look at this face. -Oh!
這難道不是你見過最美的臉嗎
Isn't this the most beautiful face you've ever seen?
第二 第二美麗
Second. Second most beautiful.
她對你太好了
She's too good for you!
我不記得第一次了
And also, I don't remember the first time I did this,
那並不對
and that doesn't feel right.
所以 凱特
So, Kate,
你願意再次嫁給我嗎
will you marry me again?
天哪
Holy crap.
嗯!
Yeah!
是的 我願意
Yes! Yes, I will!
-她說她願意 -她說她願意
-She said yes! -She said yes!
我說我願意 裏奧
That's what I'm talking about, Leo!
媽媽
Go, Mom!
我說我願意 兄弟
That's what I'm talking about, bro!
這是我的男孩
That's my boy right there.
好的 這是愛 寶貝
Okay, that's love, baby.
現在 紳士 達達尼昂說 沒有解釋他的行為
"'And now, gentlemen, ' said d'Artagnan, without stopping to explain his conduct,
我為人人 人人為我
"'all for one, and one for all.
這是我們的座右銘 不是嗎
"'That is our motto, is it not?
但是 看這裏
"'But still, look here.'"
哇
Wow.
這是誰的昂貴的車
Whose fancy car is that?
這太酷了
That's so cool.
他已經遭受太多了 我們不要給他施加壓力
He's been through a lot. Let's not overwhelm him.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Papi!
蘇菲亞
Sofia!
嗨 瑪格達
Hi, Magda!
讓我把這個放進家裏
Let me just drop this in the house.
嘿
Hey.
爸爸
Papi.
蘇菲亞
Sofia.
瑪格達
Magda.
天哪 我記得
Oh, my God, I remember.
我是萊昂納多黑山
I'm Leonardo Montenegro.
凱特
Kate!
我痊癒了
I'm cured!
醫生說我的記憶會瞬間回來
The doctor said my memory could come back suddenly,
他是對的
and he was right.
我說 我看到爸爸了
I mean, I saw Papi...
我從他身邊走過走進屋子
I walked past him into the house and poof!
記憶回來了
It came back!
親愛的 問我任何事吧
Honey, ask me anything.
問我在墨西哥城的童年吧
Ask me about my childhood in Mexico City.
關於我對汽車的收藏
About my car collection.
關於我的錢
About my money.
錢 我有錢
Money. I have money!
很多很多錢
Lots and lots of money.
這是我人生中最快樂的日子
This is the happiest day
of my life!
等下
Wait.
你不是我的妻子
You're not my wife.
為什麼你讓我以為
Why would you make me think...
為什麼你對我這麼做
Why would you do that to me?
我知道為什麼
I know why.
你就是那個討厭我的糟糕的地毯清潔工
You're that awful carpet cleaner lady who hates me.
而且
And...
他們是你的孩子
And these are your kids
你讓我相信
and you made me believe...
天哪
Oh, God.
你戲弄了我
You tricked me.
你利用了我
You used me.
裏奧...
Leo...
啊 啊 別
No, no, no.
我不叫裏奧
My name is not Leo.
我是萊昂納多
It's Leonardo.
而且 我和你沒有任何關係
And I don't belong with you.
也不是她們的爸爸
And I don't belong with them.
我要去拿我的東西
I'll get my things.
裏面沒有一樣東西是我的
There's nothing in there that's mine.
不管有沒有用
For what it's worth...
我還是想跟你說聲 對不起
I'm sorry.
還有...
And...
還有謝謝你
And thank you.
快來 兒子
Come on, son.
嘿
Hey.
女孩們
Girls.
別走!
Don't go!
爸爸!爸爸!不要走
Dad! Dad! Don't go.
爸爸!爸爸!
Dad! Dad!
爸爸!
Dad!
別啊!不要走 你不要走!
No! Don't go, don't go!
等等 不要
Wait, no.
爸比!
Daddy!
爸比 等等!
Daddy, wait!
歡迎回來 先生
Welcome back, sir.
順便一說 您的葬禮還挺可愛的
Your funeral was lovely, by the way.
我還是更喜歡爸爸調的醬料
I liked Dad's sauce better.
寶貝兒 他根本不是你爸爸 你知道的
Sweetie, you know he was never really your dad.
當時你就應該把他攔下來
You should have tried to stop him.
我能說什麼?
What was I gonna say?
我騙了他 我幾乎是把他綁架了
I lied to him. I basically kidnapped the man.
那又怎樣?很明顯你已經完全愛上他了
So what? You're obviously totally in love with him.
現在重點不是這個!
What does it matter now?
他回歸了他從前的生活
He's back to his old life,
身邊有傭人 有超模
with his servants and supermodels.
一切都已經結束了
It's over.
趕緊吃飯吧 外婆還等著見你們呢
Now finish up, 'cause Grandma can't wait to see ya.
你讓我很高興
我的父親
萊昂納多黑山 一百年前創立了這家公司
現在我可以退休了
我相信我的兒子
萊昂納多balabala黑山
將帶領我們走向未來
什麼
你說過要我來管理公司的
好吧.
既來之則安之 我要隨遇而安
不要沮喪
我還需要你的幫助
這些對我來說都是陌生的
但我有一些想法
看看 他都已經有想法了
比如說.
除了90磅的袋裝水泥
我們還應當出售30磅的
這麼做的原因是
你們知道那會增加多少生產成本嗎?
一個棒球場
三百萬 一年
你們以前有沒有搬過一袋水泥?
能讓你疝氣
誰在乎?
搬水泥的人
你聽到這胡話了嗎?
給他點時間吧 瑪格達
這個新手將成為一個強者
不用了 我不喝酒
No, I don't drink.
哎 等等 我是要喝酒的
Wait, wait. I do drink.
把它倒滿 柯林!
Fill her up, Colin!
好的 這才是我記憶中的樣子 先生
Yes, that was definitely my recollection, sir.
-給我酒瓶 -啊哈 我想什麼來著
-Give me the bottle. -Ah, what was I thinking?
這也太可怕了
This is horrifying.
她為什麼要演這個?
Why is she doing this?
因為人生苦短 而你又不想抱憾終身
Because life's short, and you don't wanna have regrets.
走吧 我們去找裏奧
Come on. We're getting Leo.
耶!!!!
Yay!
抱歉 肚子疼 請讓一讓
Excuse us. Diarrhea. Excuse us.
你們要去哪兒?
Where are you going?
-我會打給你的 -演出很棒!
-I'll call you. -Yes, yes, yes!
快點兒 我們去追上他
Hurry up, we gotta catch him.
先生 您應該打給我的
Sir, you should have called me.
然後我會把這個拿過去給您
I'd have gotten that for you.
你知道嗎 太有意思了
You know, it's funny.
這艘船陪伴我10年了
I've had this boat for 10 years,
這塊地方我卻從未踏足
and I don't think I ever stepped foot in here.
好吧 那是因為您有傭人
Well, that's because you have people
幫您照料一切
to take care of everything for you.
你知道嗎 我當建築工人時
You know, when I was working construction,
特別討厭像我這種有錢的蠢貨
I hated rich assholes like me.
呃...
Hmm.
你討厭過我嗎 柯林?你可以實話實說
Did you hate me, Colin? You can be honest.
呃 我得提醒您一下下 先生
Well. If I may remind you, sir,
就是因為上個管家太誠實 我才得到這份工作的
the reason I got this job was because the last steward was honest.
啊哈
Eh.
我能說件事嗎?
Can I confess something?
嗯…
Hmm.
我不太確定我該去過哪種生活了
I'm not exactly sure where I fit in anymore.
聽上去是不是太瘋狂了?
Is that crazy?
大多數人都只見識過自己生活的世界
Most of us only know the world that we're born into.
您有幸從一個完全不同的角度領悟了人生
You've had the privilege of seeing life from an entirely different perspective.
是啊 確實如此
Yeah, I did.
而且那種日子糟透了 不是嗎?
And it sucked, didn't it?
怎麼啦 凱特?
What's up, Kate?
鮑比 我們要借你的船!
Bobby, we need your boat!
你聽到了?她要借我的船
You hear that? She needs my boat.
她需要它
She needs it.
早上好 爸比
早安 兒子
喝咖啡嗎?
好的 謝謝
我們正享受一個好天氣
是的
那是什麼?!
太陽為什麼從那裏升起?
因為我們返回了俄勒岡州
什麼?為什麼?!
和那個騙子在一起?
當然不是!
我不同意!
爸爸 等等
我們商量一下
不!我要這艘船現在掉頭!
我們回墨西哥!
爸爸 聽我說
這太荒謬了
發生了什麼?
我正在阻止你的弟弟
毀掉他自己的生活
為了什麼披薩護士!
我是一個成年人!我可以和任何我想要的人待在一起
是的 跟隨你的內心吧
公司怎麼辦?
你有責任要承擔
一生中只一次 做正確的事吧!
這是我的第一次!
我喜歡這個新的萊昂納多 太浪漫了
我是說 放手向前吧
真的?
是的 你當然想讓他從照片裏出來
看看我找到了什麼...
在一個叫做 海灘拾荒物 的東西上
有個乘遊艇的墨西哥城女人
有可能是他姐姐
那是你
什麼?
你在醫院裏故意丟下了萊昂納多
這是真的嗎?
當然不是
那不會是一個來自墨西哥的女人...
遊艇還停靠在俄勒岡州海岸
當然 因為那樣的人太多了
你把他丟在了這裏!
-詛咒你!-拜託 爸爸 你知道我絕不會...
閉嘴!
她失去了理智!
你太陰險了!
閉嘴!
你是個壞人!
三聲
Three.
三聲! 那是凱特!
Three! That's Kate!
那個人是凱特
That's Kate.
萊昂納多
Leonardo.
走開 船長
Move away, Captain.
阿圖羅!阿圖羅!
Arturo! Arturo!
卡塔莉娜!卡塔莉娜!
Catalina! Catalina!
-他們轉向了! -媽媽!媽媽!媽媽!
-They're turning! -Mom! Mom! Mom!
他們掉頭了 他們為什麼要掉頭?
They're turning around. Why are they turning around?
-我不知道 -鮑比 快做些什麼呀
-I don't know. -Bobby, do something.
別 別 別!
No, no, no!
爸爸!
別掉頭!
快打開門!
爸爸 求您了!
讓我進去!
不行!你已經被那個女人洗腦了!
快點 快點 我們要追不上他們了!
Come on, come on, we're losing them!
這船就不能再快些了嗎?
Can't this thing go any faster?
不行親愛的 這只是艘遊船
No, it's a leisure boat, babe!
承認吧 你就是買虧了!
Just admit you overpaid.
我買虧了 行了吧!
Okay, okay, I overpaid!
我們沒可能追上他們了
We're never gonna catch them.
我該花錢買個40英尺的遊艇
I should have sprung for the 40-footer.
很抱歉凱特 我也幫不上忙了
I'm sorry, Kate. There's nothing I can do.
我愛你 凱特!
I love you, Kate!
我也愛你!
I love you, too!
他在幹什麼?
What's he doing?
-天哪! -我的天!太了不起了!
-Oh, my God! -Whoa! That was amazing!
有人落水!
Man overboard!
那個傻子!
That fool!
控制住船舵!
Take the helm!
-什麼?凱特! -媽媽!
-What? Kate! -Mom!
-媽媽! -凱特
-Mom! -Kate.
我來了!
I'm coming!
媽媽! 你要幹什麼?
Mom! What are you doing?
你愣著幹啥?快去拿救生艇!
What are you waiting for? Get the dinghy!
快去拿救生艇啊兄弟!
Get the dinghy, bro!
我再也不要和你分開了!
I never want to be apart from you!
我再也不會讓你離開了!
I'll never let you go again!
萊昂納多!
如果你這麼做...
那就此結束!
你別再回來了!
我不管!
我愛她!
兄弟 我還從沒真正這樣做過
我將和你斷絕關係!
我發誓!
那就這樣吧!
你將被剝奪繼承權!
你名下不會有一分錢!
分文不給?
什麼都沒有!
你將成為一個貧民!
等等!等等!
我們都別激動!
我們可以協商一下!
比如說我保留瑞士的賬戶?
不!
媽媽!爸爸他在幹什麼?
Mom! What is he doing?
我不知道!
I don't know!
我在協商!
I'm negotiating!
凱特 快上來!你會溺水的 快點!
Kate, get in here! You're gonna drown. Come on!
也別再想經營黑山的工廠!
裏奧!
你的姐姐會接管它!
我受寵若驚 爸爸
不是你
我會把它交給索菲亞
你把你的弟弟遺棄了
你解雇我了?
你把我從這個家族裏剔除了?
當然沒有
我們將你調去負責我們的慈善事業
那些有怪味的 貧窮的小孩?
是的
你太遲鈍了!
兒子 仔細聽
親愛的 你不上來嗎?
Honey, are you coming?
這是你最後的機會
那你能不能
每月給我點生活費
不能!
現在的情景和我想像的不一樣
This is not how I envisioned this moment.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
只是絕大多數人從來都不會
It's just that most people don't actually
真的有在金錢和愛情之間選擇的機會
have to choose between love and money.
這不容易
It's not easy.
那就給一筆行不行
不行!
簡單了 我選你
It's easy. I choose you.
哦 裏奧 你在放棄一大堆的東西 兄弟
Oye, Leo, you're giving up a lot, dude.
如果你需要幾分鐘想想 沒人會怪你的
No one would begrudge you if you wanted to take a few minutes.
博比 你能別管這事了嗎?
Bobby, would you stay out of this?
啥?我只是想說
What? I'm just saying!
愛情會消退的 好嗎?我的意思是 愛情很美好
Love fades, okay? I mean, it's wonderful.
但是當激情消退的時候 這個時候錢...
But some of the excitement goes away. Now, money...
博比! 你給我閉嘴!
Bobby! Shut the hell up!
-親愛的你才閉嘴!  -你閉嘴!
-You shut up, babe!  -Yeah! Shut the hell up!
凱特 聽著
Kate, listen.
和你一起貧窮的日子比
My life was richer when I was poor with you
和我擁有全世界的錢的時候要富有的多
than when I had all the money in the world.
如果我再跳進水裏一次
If I jump back in the water,
你能保證這回會親我嗎?
Will you promise to kiss me this time?
我會的
Yes.
先生 你想收留我嗎?
Sir, do you want to adopt me?
加油 凱特!
Go, Kate!
天啊
Ay.
一個失憶的富豪
A rich guy with amnesia,
一個慷慨的貧窮女孩
a big-hearted poor girl,
一個不支持的父親 一個邪惡的姐姐
a disapproving father, an evil sister...
現實生活比浪漫電視劇還要精彩
Real life is better than a telenovela.
媽媽好棒!
Go, Mom!
午餐準備好了!
Lunches are done!
博比五分鐘內會來接我
Bobby's picking me up in five.
好的 你確定今天你能接孩子們放學嗎?
All right. You sure you can pick up the girls from school today?
-嗯 啊  -我去開
-Uh, yeah.  -I got it.
埃米莉 告訴他我馬上過去
Emily, tell him I'm coming.
我能
Yes.
然後我會載奧利維亞去橄欖球訓練
Then I'll drop Olivia at football practice,
但是得由你來負責接她
but you have to pick her up.
-科林?  -又見面了
-Colin?  -Hello again.
天啊怎麼回事?
What on Earth?
嘿 過來
Hey, come here.
你怎麼過來了?
What are you doing here?
我還以為你會在人才市場
I was hoping you might be in the market
想要找一個被強烈推薦的一流的蘇格蘭保姆
for a top-notch, Scottish nanny with excellent references.
你知道我超愛那樣
You know I'd love that
但是我們完全付不起你的工資
but there's no way we can afford you.
其實你能 先生
Well, in fact you can, sir.
索非亞用遊艇把我送回來
Sofia sent me back with the yacht.
她是想讓我提醒你
She wanted to remind you
這曾是一個來自父親的生日禮物
It was a birthday present from your father.
文書上的名字是你 這還是你的遊艇
The deed is in your name. It's still yours.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你的意思是我是可以把它賣了?
You mean I can sell it?
這肯定是一大筆錢
It must be worth a fortune.
至少六千萬
Over 60 million.
比索?【墨西哥貨幣單位】
Pesos?
噢 不是的 夫人 是美元
God, no, ma'am. Dollars.
以挪威皇家海軍賦予我的權利
By the power invested in me by the Royal Norwegian Navy,
我宣佈你們現在結為夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以親吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
啊媽媽!
Go, Mom!
爸爸!
Go, Dad!
好了
Okay.
在我為這對幸福的夫妻祝詞之前
Before I toast the happy couple,
請允許我先澄清一些誤會
let me just dispel a few rumors
最近總是被提起
that have been floating around
關於我被戴綠帽子了
about me being cheated on.
從來沒發生過 好嗎? 以前沒有 以後也沒有
Never happened. Okay? Not once, not ever.
有太多的話我想說了
There's just so much I wanna say.
但是我不是個詩人
But I'm not a poet.
我無法用語言表達
I don't have words.
但我可以用音樂
I have music.
我為萊昂納多感到非常高興
I'm very happy for Leonardo.
你為萊昂納多感到非常高興
You are very happy for Leonardo.
她為萊昂納多感到非常高興
She is very happy for Leonardo.
我很抱歉我沒有辦法現場祝賀你們
I'm so sorry I couldn't be there to celebrate with you.
但是我現在在菲律賓
But I'm here in the Philippines,
作為黑山共和國的兒童教育計劃的先鋒人員
spearheading the Montenegros' Children's Education Initiative,
而且 哦 我在這一直幫助這些孩子
and, oh, I've been here helping these kids
過上更快樂 更美好的生活 他們超級喜歡我的
have a happier, better life, and they adore me.
-是不是?  -沒
-Right?  -No.
當我們認識的時候
When we first met,
我是個接球手
I was the catch. Okay?
我是足球隊的
I was the football player.
我是個四分衛 好吧?
I was the quarterback, all right?
她甚至連個啦啦隊員都不是
She didn't even make cheerleader.
她是喝彩的人
She was on the spirit squad.
當我看著裏奧...
When I look at Leo...
當我看著凱特...
When I look at Kate...
當我看著他們在一起...
When I look at Leo and Kate...
這是維托柯里昂的名言
The words of Vito Corleone.
維托柯里昂是電影教父中的人物
一個聰明的男人 一個男人擁有智慧
A wise man. A man of intelligence.
沒錯 他殺了很多人
Sure, he killed many people.
但總是為了工作...從不為娛樂
But always for work... never for pleasure.
現在 我是在後台
Right now, I'm backstage
在金色池塘退休之家
at the Golden Pond Retirement Home,
秀才剛剛落幕五分鐘
about five minutes from curtain.
Hodel是主角17歲的女兒
我扮演 屋頂上的小提琴手 裏的霍德爾
I'm playing Hodel in Fiddler on the Roof.
我認為現在非常適合討論下零花錢的問題
And I thought now was a good time to talk about allowance.
當你為了娛樂而刺傷他人...
When you stab somebody for pleasure...
你裁斷了他的五臟六腑
you cut out his intestines and guts.
裏奧爸爸會做我吃過的最好吃的意大利面 ♪
♪ Leo has the best spaghetti I ever tasted
我這輩子從來沒有在一個婚禮上
I have never in all my puff been at a wedding
一個有著免費酒吧的婚禮
where there's been a free bar.
一般來說 他們最後會考慮賬單的問題
Usually, at the end, they tries to settle up the bill.
他們會說"噢不 我沒帶錢"
And they're, "Oh, no, I didn't have it."
"我有的只有啤酒 你這個"
"I only had beer, you"
婚禮上總是會有個
There's always a at a wedding.
萊奧納多
Leonardo.
你仍然被剝奪繼承權
You're still disinherited.
但我仍會將遊艇買走
But I'm still going to buy the yacht.
不是為了你
Not for you.
是為了我美麗的孫女們
For my beautiful granddaughters.
他們值得整個世界
They deserve the world.
博比讓我讀一個準備好的聲明
Bobby has asked me to read a prepared statement.
"我從來沒有背叛過的我丈夫
"I never cheated on my husband.
我永遠不會
I never would.
任何一個女人都不會"
No woman ever would."
你剝離皮膚和肉
..you peel back the skin and muscle.
你取出五臟六腑
You take out the guts... the intestines...
胰腺...腎臟和...
the pancreas... the kidneys and...
無論如何 祝福這對新人
Anyway, congratulations to the happy couple.
-哇!-乾杯
-Mwah! -Cheers.
-嗯
-Mmm.
-啊
-Ah!
-哇吼!
-Whoo!